<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.blogger.com/styles/atom.css" type="text/css"?><feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom' xmlns:openSearch='http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/'><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-8729083</id><updated>2008-06-04T15:40:42.063-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Twin Sunset</title><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://glyph.twistedmatrix.com/'/><link rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://glyph.twistedmatrix.com/feeds/posts/default'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://glyph.twistedmatrix.com/feeds/posts/default'/><author><name>glyph</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/07021175796928101086</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email></author><generator version='7.00' uri='http://www.blogger.com'>Blogger</generator><openSearch:totalResults>6</openSearch:totalResults><openSearch:startIndex>1</openSearch:startIndex><openSearch:itemsPerPage>25</openSearch:itemsPerPage><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-8729083.post-9059370622388794456</id><published>2008-06-04T13:04:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2008-06-04T13:04:36.929-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Data In, Garbage Out</title><content type='html'>&lt;blockquote&gt;"The string is a stark data structure and everywhere it is passed there is much duplication of process. It is a perfect vehicle for hiding information." —&lt;a href="http://www.cs.yale.edu/quotes.html"&gt; Alan Perlis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;I switched to blogger recently expecting a more "professional" blogging experience.&amp;nbsp; I thought I'd be able to use a GUI editor and not concern myself with the details of the blog engine.&amp;nbsp; Apparently I was wrong.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Writing that last post, I had some pretty serious problems with getting the formatting to come out right.&amp;nbsp; Blogger does a couple of really terrible things:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;When you switch between "Compose" and "Edit HTML" views, some amount of whitespace (although not all of it) is destroyed.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Even when posting using the ATOM API, the posted HTML is mangled in semi-arbitrary ways.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Properly-quoted "&amp;lt;" and "&amp;gt;" (i.e. "&amp;amp;lt;" and "&amp;amp;gt;") are quoted again.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Additional line-breaks are added.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp; is converted to white-space, and then&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;white space is collapsed.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;This is one of the reasons that I'm such a stickler for treating data as structured data, and not making arbitrary heuristic guesses about it.&amp;nbsp; It's not just a matter of handling obscure, nerdy edge cases that average users won't run into.&amp;nbsp; In fact, it's the opposite.&amp;nbsp; Nerds (like myself) can figure out whether you're double-quoting your HTML entities or doing improper whitespace conversions.&amp;nbsp; But what does a regular Joe do when a "frustrated" smiley ("&amp;gt;.&amp;lt;") gets converted into some incomprehensible soup of HTML?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I was reminded of this same issue when reading &lt;a href="http://wiki.habariproject.org/en/XHTML_vs_HTML"&gt;a page on the Habari wiki&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;"If you are going to produce real XHTML in a tool usable by ordinary users, then you &lt;b&gt;cannot&lt;/b&gt; do it by string concatenation. You need to assemble your content by serializing an XML DOM tree. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you want to allow plugins, then your plugin API &lt;i&gt;cannot&lt;/i&gt; allow plugin authors to stick arbitrary strings in the output. Rather, they should be allowed to add nodes to the DOM tree, or to manipulate existing ones."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;Strangely enough, this page concludes that the important thing is not to build their next-generation blogging tool on top of a technology that lets them produce valid output (serializing DOM trees) but that the important thing is not producing valid output, but string concatenation.&amp;nbsp; They very clearly put an implementation technique above a good experience for users.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(This is your brain.&amp;nbsp; This is your brain on PHP.&amp;nbsp; Any questions?)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I don't want to pick on the Habari developers overmuch.&amp;nbsp; After all, the problem that inspired this post was with Blogger, and Wordpress has the same issue.&amp;nbsp; In fact, the Habari guys are mostly notable for having considered the implications of their decision so carefully; it's just a surprise to me that they walked all the way up to the right answer, looked at it, made sure it was right, and then decided to ignore it and keep on going.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Here's the surprise for the Habari developers, and basically everyone else who writes web applications that process HTML: &lt;i&gt;it has nothing to do with XHTML&lt;/i&gt;.&amp;nbsp; It is a general principle of software development.&amp;nbsp; The only reason you &lt;i&gt;notice&lt;/i&gt; when you're doing XHTML is that the browser isn't correcting for hundreds of minor mistakes, and rather than screwing up immediately it screws up one time in a thousand when a user managed to type a "&amp;lt;" or a "&amp;amp;".&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You know what else you can't build with string concatenation?&amp;nbsp; AVIs.&amp;nbsp; PNGs.&amp;nbsp; SWFs.&amp;nbsp; Lots of data on the web is treated as structured, but only because &lt;i&gt;it's too hard&lt;/i&gt; for the people who generally build web applications to generate it.&amp;nbsp; If you want to write a program that takes input processes it, and returns output, you need an intermediary structure to hold that data so that you can ensure its validity.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;That's not to say that it's always a bad idea to have user interfaces that allow people to type in a syntax that they know and understand, like an "HTML" view.&amp;nbsp; Those interfaces might even be forgiving and correct for lots of errors.&amp;nbsp; Adding line-breaks so that people can type newlines in a mishmash of pseudo-HTML is okay, as long as you know where that ends and your actual structured content begins.&amp;nbsp; For example, if you include a WYSIWYG GUI editor, you should probably internally make sure that WYS really is WYG and you're not making the same kind of heuristic guesses about the data that &lt;i&gt;your own tool&lt;/i&gt; generated as some stuff that a user with only a smattering of HTML knowledge typed in directly.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Keeping structured data structured is near and dear to my heart in large part because as systems get &lt;a href="http://oubiwann.blogspot.com/2008/05/required-reading-ultra-large-systems.html"&gt;ultra large&lt;/a&gt;, the different pieces need to be able to talk to each other using clear and unambiguous formats.&amp;nbsp; These points of integration, the places where system A talks to system B (a blogging system talks to a web browser or a blogging client, for example) are absolutely the most critical pieces to test, test, and test again.&amp;nbsp; If you have a bug in your system, you can find it and fix it; but if you have a bug which only arises from an &lt;i&gt;interaction&lt;/i&gt; between your system and two others, your test environment needs to be 3 times bigger, and the error is at least 3 times harder to catch.&amp;nbsp; But it gets worse.&amp;nbsp; If you're dealing with 4 systems, then your test environment is 4 times bigger - but the bug is 6 times harder to catch.&amp;nbsp; And so on.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Fred Brooks observed that &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Mythical_Man-Month"&gt;adding more programmers to a project running behind schedule makes it later&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; This is because of the additional channels of communication.&amp;nbsp; Now imagine that one of your developers has a curious speech defect: when he says "lasagna" he actually means "critical bug", and vice versa.&amp;nbsp; When he hears one, he understands it as the other.&amp;nbsp; Working alone, this is a harmless eccentricity, but as soon as you put other developers into the mix, strange effects start taking place.&amp;nbsp; He desperately tries to tell them about the delicious lasagna he had last night, and they can't understand why he's losing sleep over it.&amp;nbsp; Or, he is sanguine as his fellow engineers tell him about all the italian food they're eating, while the business is &lt;a href="http://thedailywtf.com/Articles/Deploy%21--Deploy%21-Deploy%21.aspx"&gt;losing millions of dollars&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It's sort of like if every time he said "&amp;lt;" the other developers understood him to mean "&amp;amp;lt;".&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If I ever have more than a few hours to work on it, eventually I'll deploy &lt;a href="http://divmod.org/trac/wiki/DivmodHyperbola"&gt;my own blogging platform&lt;/a&gt; and I'll know that it can handle HTML correctly.&amp;nbsp; Until then though, I've worked out a strategy for posting to blogger which seems to mostly preserve the formatting that I want to see.&amp;nbsp; I figure that other Python developers might be interested in this, since I frequently see posts to blogger which eat indentation.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;I use &lt;a href="http://www.scribefire.com/"&gt;ScribeFire&lt;/a&gt; as my HTML editor.&amp;nbsp; It manages OK, except it doesn't include linebreaks, &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;s or &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;s to separate lines.&amp;nbsp; So, leave the "Convert Line Breaks" option &lt;i&gt;on&lt;/i&gt; in your blog's settings.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;In "Settings -&amp;gt; Basic -&amp;gt; Global Settings", disable "show compose mode for all your blogs".&amp;nbsp; The compose view is destructive, and switching between it and "Edit HTML" will eat whitespace each time you do it; it also seems to sometimes eat bits of formatting when you publish even if it's just on the page.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Edit a post in ScribeFire.&amp;nbsp; To save drafts, use the "save as note" functionality.&amp;nbsp; This doesn't publish it to be a blogger draft, but there's no way to get the data into blogger directly.&amp;nbsp; You can use the HTML tab as you normally would, to add tags that aren't supported (such as "&amp;lt;pre&amp;gt;").&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Switch to the HTML ("&amp;lt;A&amp;gt;") tab in scribefire.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;select all.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;copy.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Click "New Post" in the blogger web UI.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;click in the text field.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;paste.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;The presence of numerous properly-escaped HTML characters in this post should be an indication that it works.</content><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://glyph.twistedmatrix.com/2008/06/data-in-garbage-out.html' title='Data In, Garbage Out'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=8729083&amp;postID=9059370622388794456' title='1 Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://glyph.twistedmatrix.com/feeds/9059370622388794456/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://glyph.twistedmatrix.com/feeds/posts/default/9059370622388794456'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/8729083/posts/default/9059370622388794456'/><author><name>glyph</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/07021175796928101086</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-8729083.post-2248439228258171279</id><published>2008-06-03T18:08:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2008-06-04T11:58:22.785-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Memeventory! Inventomeme? Uh, how about "inventory meme".</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;A long time ago — when these sorts of things were still a going concern commercially, if that dates it for you — I remember debating the "realism" of interactive fiction (at the time, "text adventures").  A key point in the discussion was the kleptocratic structure of the game.  I wish I could remember this better.  For example, I wish I remember who I was talking to.  I do, however, remember the critical line, "no actual adult walks around with a bag full of that much crap".  I was reminded of this by &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/paulswartz/statuses/826273959"&gt;Paul Swartz describing the contents of &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; bag&lt;/a&gt;.   A typical "adventurer" will have at least a dozen small trinkets, gewgaws and baubles on their person at any given time.  These are critical work their way out of whatever jam they happen to be in at the moment.  Memorably, sometimes they will also be carrying &lt;a href="http://www.oldmanmurray.com/features/78.html"&gt;maple syrup, masking tape, other people's passports, and cat fur&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Granted, I don't have any syrup on me at the moment.  I do have a few other bits of technological detritus on my person; more, I think than the average adventure-game protagonist.  Now that I'm an actual adult, to win this at-least-a-decade-old argument with someone I can't even remember, I'm going to prove it — and you're going to help me do it!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Okay, okay.  You came here to memeplex the blogosphere or whatever the kids are calling it these days, not to listen to me ramble about text adventures or my vindictive streak.  So here's the idea.  Get ready to head out of your house, office, or apartment — wherever you happen to be reading this post — and then take an inventory of your personal flotsam.  Then, post it to your weblog in the style of an adventure game.  In true Glyph style (i.e. more complicated than necessary), I used &lt;a href="http://divmod.org/trac/wiki/DivmodImaginary"&gt;Imaginary&lt;/a&gt; to assist me with this task.  In order to see the list below in all three of its &lt;i&gt;glorious&lt;/i&gt; colors, &lt;a href="https://code.launchpad.net/%7Eglyph/+junk/inventorize"&gt;you'll have to grab the code from launchpad&lt;/a&gt; as well as &lt;a href="http://divmod.org/trac/wiki/CombinatorTutorial"&gt;figure out how to set up its dependencies&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Without further ado, here it is:&lt;pre style="font-family: monospace;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You are carrying:&lt;br /&gt; a digital watch&lt;br /&gt; a bluetooth stereo headset&lt;br /&gt; a grey messenger bag&lt;br /&gt;  the grey messenger bag contains:&lt;br /&gt;   a mobile phone&lt;br /&gt;   a black macbook&lt;br /&gt;   a macbook MagSafe(TM) power brick&lt;br /&gt;   a small orange microfiber cloth&lt;br /&gt;   a mini-DVI to VGA adapter&lt;br /&gt;   a beige graph-paper notebook&lt;br /&gt;   a 4' USB mini-B to A cable&lt;br /&gt; a wallet&lt;br /&gt;  the wallet contains:&lt;br /&gt;   a borders rewards card&lt;br /&gt;   a boloco frequent burrito-er card&lt;br /&gt;   a $35 in cash&lt;br /&gt;   a CharlieCard (TM)&lt;br /&gt;   a Massachusetts driver's license&lt;br /&gt;   a fortune from a fortune cookie&lt;br /&gt; a keychain&lt;br /&gt;  the keychain contains:&lt;br /&gt;   a samsung MicroSD-HC reader&lt;br /&gt;    the samsung MicroSD-HC reader contains:&lt;br /&gt;     a 1GB MicroSD card&lt;br /&gt;   a RFID building key&lt;br /&gt;   an apartment key&lt;br /&gt;   a car key&lt;br /&gt;   a mailbox key&lt;br /&gt;   an office outer door key&lt;br /&gt;   an office inner door key&lt;br /&gt;   a shaw's rewards card&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;Rather than the usual fixed number of additional participants, I'm going to say that you can tag one person for each container in your list.  I've got 4 (wallet, messenger bag, keychain, microSD reader), so I will tag &lt;a href="http://radix.twistedmatrix.com/"&gt;radix,&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://tenth.livejournal.com/"&gt;tenth,&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://jcalderone.livejournal.com/"&gt;exarkun,&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://washort.twistedmatrix.com/"&gt;washort&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;You get bonus points for generating the list using a program, double-bonus points for using Imaginary and quadruple-bucky-points for &lt;a href="http://divmod.org/trac/query?status=new&amp;amp;status=assigned&amp;amp;amp;amp;status=reopened&amp;amp;amp;amp;component=Imaginary&amp;amp;amp;amp;order=priority"&gt;resolving an Imaginary ticket&lt;/a&gt; while you're at it.  This goes for everyone tagged by this meme, not just my tag-ees.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;If the resulting score increase causes you to gain a level, I will notify you by e-mail.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-style: italic;"&gt;(Apologies for the repeated edits.  Blogger seems to have a problem with &lt;strike&gt;&amp;lt;pre&amp;gt; tags&lt;/strike&gt; &lt;strike&gt;HTML&lt;/strike&gt; everything.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://glyph.twistedmatrix.com/2008/06/memeventory-inventomeme-uh-how-about.html' title='Memeventory! Inventomeme? Uh, how about &amp;quot;inventory meme&amp;quot;.'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=8729083&amp;postID=2248439228258171279' title='2 Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://glyph.twistedmatrix.com/feeds/2248439228258171279/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://glyph.twistedmatrix.com/feeds/posts/default/2248439228258171279'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/8729083/posts/default/2248439228258171279'/><author><name>glyph</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/07021175796928101086</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-8729083.post-3487586246737130733</id><published>2008-04-10T11:20:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2008-04-10T11:20:33.618-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Structured Python Editor</title><content type='html'>&lt;div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'&gt;If you're not already familiar with Subtext, you should probably &lt;a href='http://subtextual.org/subtext2.html'&gt;watch this video&lt;/a&gt; to learn about it.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I'm not a big fan of the Subtext programming model.  But it does convey one idea that I really, really like.  &lt;i&gt;Programs are structured data&lt;/i&gt;.  This is a very powerful idea, and I think it's a pity that it hasn't really caught on.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Most programmers subscribe to the idea of &lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Model-view-controller'&gt;model/view separation&lt;/a&gt;; this phrase has especially come back into vogue with the popularity of systems like &lt;a href='http://www.djangoproject.com/'&gt;Django&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href='http://rubyonrails.org/'&gt;Rails&lt;/a&gt;.  But programmers are only a fan of this as far as it comes to "end-user" applications.  For our own tools, rigidly gluing the model to the view (and both the model and the view to the persistence format, execution model, and innumerable other details) is the order of the day.  Indeed, Python's own popularity is due in large part to the &lt;a href='http://www.devchix.com/2007/05/24/beautiful-python-the-programming-language-that-taught-me-how-to-love-again/'&gt;relative beauty&lt;/a&gt; of its syntax.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;One of the problems this causes is a &lt;a href='http://r0ml.net/blog/2006/05/10/atualizao'&gt;language gap&lt;/a&gt;.  Guido mentioned this in his Py3K talk: different programming communities are already choosing identifiers based on their natural languages.  The conflation of real-names and binding-names also creates a more subtle problem in Python: when you want to deprecate a name, let's say, &lt;code&gt;twisted.web.server,&lt;/code&gt; you have to choose another name — probably one which isn't as good.  If the binding name were, as in Subtext, an internal identifier rather than the user interface accessible to everyone, this would be an easier thing to do.  For that matter, a large part of the Py3K effort itself is a change to Python's user interface; if Python were an interactive program with a separated model and view, it would be much easier to change this without changing everyone's code at the same time.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;IDEs like &lt;a href='http://pydev.sourceforge.net/'&gt;PyDev for Eclipse&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href='http://wingware.com/wingide/index'&gt;Wing IDE&lt;/a&gt; don't really address the problem of "program as bag of bytes".  They provide tools, it's true, but those tools still treat a program as semi-structured information.  One of the things you do most frequently in an IDE like this is type some code, which at least temporarily puts your program into a totally invalid state.  As you're typing "def ", your module is syntactically invalid.  Once you've finished adding arguments, and a docstring or method body it's valid again, but only until you make your next change.  If you're using a tool to edit something &lt;i&gt;other&lt;/i&gt; than a program, like, say, &lt;a href='http://inkscape.org/'&gt;Inkscape&lt;/a&gt;, as you move between different states in your drawing (add a line, change a gradient, resize a shape) each one is a valid SVG document if you were to save it.  This is one of the reasons that I don't really use IDEs; despite their features, the core of the experience is still hammering away on a bunch of text files, and for that, it is &lt;i&gt;very&lt;/i&gt; hard to beat &lt;a href='http://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/'&gt;Emacs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;IDEs aren't the only tools which could benefit from a truly structured interpretation of code.  Version control systems, for example, could benefit immensely by having higher level operations.  How often do you really want to know "who changed this line of code last"?  I don't know about you, but personally, I want to ask questions like "when was this method defined" and "was it ever moved from another module".  These questions are difficult or impossible to ask of modern version control systems (even the really &lt;a href='http://bazaar-vcs.org/'&gt;good ones&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Another issue with programs being effectively unstructured is that they're not discoverable.  If you want to draw a line in Inkscape, you don't need to look up the SVG syntax for drawing a line; you can just hunt around for the "line" button.  This is especially important for students, who frequently forget basic things like "how do you define a method" or "what does it mean when a function is outside a class" while learning.  Squeak addresses this problem, somewhat: there's still a lot of text floating around, but your program itself is &lt;a href='http://www.mindspring.com/%7Edway/smalltalk/whisker.html'&gt;a bunch of objects you can look at&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;One of my perpetual &lt;a href='http://glyph.twistedmatrix.com/2008/04/second-week-project.html'&gt;second week project&lt;/a&gt;s is to make an IDE that understands Python as the serialization format of a graph of objects — modules, classes, and functions — rather than text.  This could work on existing Python programs, and it wouldn't need to introduce any wacky new programming paradigms in order to do it: simply treat Python as a runtime and a serialization format, and parse/serialize Python code as if it were any other type of data, like Inkscape does for SVG.  Since I'm never realistically going to do it, does anyone else want to?  Has somebody else done it already?&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://glyph.twistedmatrix.com/2008/04/structured-python-editor.html' title='Structured Python Editor'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=8729083&amp;postID=3487586246737130733' title='11 Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://glyph.twistedmatrix.com/feeds/3487586246737130733/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://glyph.twistedmatrix.com/feeds/posts/default/3487586246737130733'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/8729083/posts/default/3487586246737130733'/><author><name>glyph</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/07021175796928101086</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-8729083.post-8548422887187079740</id><published>2008-04-07T22:22:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2008-04-07T22:22:59.165-07:00</updated><title type='text'>The App Engine Of Your Internet...?</title><content type='html'>&lt;div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'&gt;I guess Google really does use Divmod as their source for new ideas!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;First, as we were implementing our email system, they launched gmail.  Then while we were working on VoIP they acquired Grand Central.  Now that we're focusing on infrastructure... they've &lt;a href='http://code.google.com/appengine/'&gt;released their infrastructure&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(If you are familiar with Axiom, the appengine &lt;a href='http://code.google.com/appengine/docs/datastore/modelclass.html#Introduction'&gt;database model example&lt;/a&gt; should be good for a &lt;a href='http://divmod.org/trac/browser/trunk/Axiom/axiom/examples/library.py'&gt;laugh&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Of course, I'm wondering: should Divmod, or me by proxy, be worried about this?  I think I've settled on "no", for a few reasons:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Google's release of appengine is an indication that this is a hot group of ideas to be working on right now.  It sets a precedent for our open source offering to be idiosyncratic.  When describing &lt;a href='http://divmod.org/trac/wiki/DivmodMantissa'&gt;Mantissa&lt;/a&gt;'s scaling model, I've often heard the objection "But with EC2 I can run whatever code I want!"  While that objection is somewhat inaccurate and I can explain with some effort that it's not true, now I have the much snappier retort: "but if you want to use Google's stuff you have to write to a specific API too".&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;You can't get all the code to appengine, at least for now, so there's a &lt;i&gt;big&lt;/i&gt; category of applications that can't use it.  We can keep working to address it — and those were really the applications we were already focused on anyway.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;appengine doesn't include &lt;a href='http://divmod.org/trac/wiki/DivmodNevow/Athena'&gt;Athena&lt;/a&gt;.  It doesn't include &lt;a href='http://divmod.org/trac/wiki/DivmodVertex'&gt;Vertex&lt;/a&gt;.  And it doesn't include &lt;a href='http://www.divmod.org/trac/wiki/DivmodImaginary'&gt;Imaginary&lt;/a&gt;.  There's plenty of fun stuff we're working on outside the realm of simply deploying a web app.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;All in all, I'm thrilled that AppEngine is in Python.  I hope that we'll be able to get &lt;a href='http://twistedmatrix.com/trac/'&gt;Twisted&lt;/a&gt; into the mix at some point, but there's always the possibility that we'll need to integrate with anything a major player releases, and I'm relieved that this (very) major player has decided to go with something that will be easy for us to talk to.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://glyph.twistedmatrix.com/2008/04/app-engine-of-your-internet.html' title='The App Engine Of Your Internet...?'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=8729083&amp;postID=8548422887187079740' title='1 Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://glyph.twistedmatrix.com/feeds/8548422887187079740/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://glyph.twistedmatrix.com/feeds/posts/default/8548422887187079740'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/8729083/posts/default/8548422887187079740'/><author><name>glyph</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/07021175796928101086</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-8729083.post-8545472962873848245</id><published>2008-04-04T22:46:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2008-04-04T22:46:37.151-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Second Week Project</title><content type='html'>&lt;div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'&gt;It seems to me that most of my friends are the sort of busy, busy people who always have a half a dozen side-projects which they have the skills but not the resources to complete.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Today, while chatting with &lt;a href='http://www.synthesisstudios.com/blog/?page_id=24'&gt;such a friend&lt;/a&gt;, he mentioned something about a project which, if he had a 2-week vacation, he'd probably be able to get to.  After spending a week sleeping, doing nothing, and puttering around, of course, he'd pick up the project in the second week.  Of course the likelihood that he would have such a vacation is basically zero, as is the likelihood that the project get done.  (Of course, anything can happen, and some things often do.)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I propose a term.  This is a &lt;i&gt;second week project&lt;/i&gt; — a project that only takes place in the second week of a hypothetical mini-sabbatical.  I feel like this could be a useful piece of shorthand for a concept which would otherwise require a few tedious sentences.  Am I right in thinking that we all have at least a few of these?&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://glyph.twistedmatrix.com/2008/04/second-week-project.html' title='Second Week Project'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=8729083&amp;postID=8545472962873848245' title='6 Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://glyph.twistedmatrix.com/feeds/8545472962873848245/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://glyph.twistedmatrix.com/feeds/posts/default/8545472962873848245'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/8729083/posts/default/8545472962873848245'/><author><name>glyph</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/07021175796928101086</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-8729083.post-6276710609691416918</id><published>2008-03-27T21:17:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2008-03-29T05:51:47.447-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Leaving Livejournal</title><content type='html'>&lt;div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'&gt;Since the &lt;a href='http://www.eweek.com/c/a/Messaging-and-Collaboration/Six-Apart-Sells-LiveJournal-to-Russias-SUP/'&gt;acquisition&lt;/a&gt;, I have been wondering if I'd leave &lt;a href='http://glyf.livejournal.com/'&gt;my LiveJournal account&lt;/a&gt; behind.  While I've been an LJ fan for a long time, Blogger has some features which make it appealing:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Nicer looking templates&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;More reserved "toolbar" area&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;More diverse client software&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Not owned by the mob&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Far more customization options and "widgets"&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://washort.twistedmatrix.com/'&gt;All&lt;/a&gt; my &lt;a href='http://radix.twistedmatrix.com/'&gt;friends&lt;/a&gt; are doing it&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Custom domain names (I've been waiting for 5 years, "glyph".lj.com isn't going anywhere...)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;"Blog" is a distinct entity from "Account"&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Blogs which have multiple contributors aren't a special thing&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Nicer profile support&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Backlinks&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;AdSense support&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Server-side drafts&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;While I plan to do more of my blogging here from now on, I don't plan to completely abandon LJ any time soon because it does have some cute other features:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;the "friends" page&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;userpics&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;moods&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;GPG public key publishing&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;I want to say something about their file-hosting feature, but that's always been kind of broken, so I've never used it.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://glyph.twistedmatrix.com/2008/03/leaving-livejournal.html' title='Leaving Livejournal'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=8729083&amp;postID=6276710609691416918' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://glyph.twistedmatrix.com/feeds/6276710609691416918/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://glyph.twistedmatrix.com/feeds/posts/default/6276710609691416918'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/8729083/posts/default/6276710609691416918'/><author><name>glyph</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/07021175796928101086</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email></author></entry></feed>