<?xml version="1.0"?><!-- RSS generated by Radio UserLand v8.2.1 on Fri, 06 Jun 2008 16:41:45 GMT --><rss version="2.0">	<channel>		<title>Zope Dispatches</title>		<link>http://radio.weblogs.com/0116506/</link>		<description>News, stories, and wisecracks from the world of Zope.</description>		<language>en-us</language>		<copyright>Copyright 2008 Paul Everitt</copyright>		<lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2008 16:41:45 GMT</lastBuildDate>		<docs>http://backend.userland.com/rss</docs>		<generator>Radio UserLand v8.2.1</generator>		<managingEditor>paul@zope-europe.org</managingEditor>		<webMaster>paul@zope-europe.org</webMaster>		<category domain="http://rpc.weblogs.com/shortChanges.xml">rssUpdates</category> 		<skipHours>			<hour>23</hour>			<hour>0</hour>			<hour>1</hour>			<hour>2</hour>			<hour>22</hour>			<hour>3</hour>			<hour>5</hour>			<hour>21</hour>			</skipHours>		<cloud domain="radio.xmlstoragesystem.com" port="80" path="/RPC2" registerProcedure="xmlStorageSystem.rssPleaseNotify" protocol="xml-rpc"/>		<ttl>60</ttl>		<item>			<title>PSPS: The Work Cycle of Theming</title>			<link>http://radio.weblogs.com/0116506/2008/06/06.html#a455</link>			<description>&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;style type=&quot;text/css&quot;&gt;body {&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; background-color: #eee;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; }&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; .document {&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; background: white;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; font-family: Georgia, serif;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; font-size: 13px;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; border: 1px #888 solid;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; padding: 0 1e&lt;/style&gt;Deliverance, DVNG, pagetypes, themesets, compiled themesets, debugability...so many words, so many details.&amp;nbsp; Let&apos;s step back and look at how an ecosystem (gag) of theming might work.&lt;div class=&quot;document&quot; id=&quot;a-small-treatise-on-theming&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This proposal describes a system where themers make themeset packages and share them at themeset sites.&amp;nbsp; Site managers can then browse, install, and update these themeset packages with a friendly user interface.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Big Goals&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;We want to make it easy for a themer to:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;simple&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Make a theme&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Share the theme with others&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;We want to make it easy for a site manager to:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;simple&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Find and use themes&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&apos;s easy to get mired in tons of details:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;simple&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Who is this &quot;themer&quot;?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;What is and isn&apos;t a &quot;sitetheme&quot;?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;What are the benefits of this approach to sitetheming?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;For now, let&apos;s focus just on how we could reinvent the process of making themes, providing something substantially easier from end-to-end.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;How It Could Work&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let&apos;s break the world of theming into 3 parts:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;first&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Make&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;nbsp; The work to produce and package a &quot;theme&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;dl class=&quot;first docutils&quot;&gt;&lt;dt&gt;&lt;em&gt;Distribute&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Put the theme in an organized place where people can find it.&amp;nbsp; This place is specifically designed to maximize convenience.&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;first&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Use&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Find available themes, use them, and get updates.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;What are some crazy things we could do to really change the game on&quot;easy&quot;?&amp;nbsp; How might we make this a significantly competitive part of our story?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Make&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deliverance helps themers avoid learning a framework&apos;s architecture and APIs.&amp;nbsp; What if they could develop and test a theme without installing any unusual software?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For example, imagine the first, simplest way to develop a theme:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;1) Create an HTML file for the theme, some CSS and images, and make sure they look alright.&amp;nbsp; This just HTML as files, so &quot;alright&quot; means&quot;Open File&quot; in a browser.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2) Next, make the Deliverance &quot;themeset&quot; file and some sample content pages.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;3) Run &quot;zip&quot; to package it all up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;4) Use &quot;curl&quot; to POST the zip file to a web service URL.&amp;nbsp; This webservice returns a packaged, compiled themeset as a zip file.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;5) Unpack the resulting zip file and view the sample content, themed as appropriate under the themeset rules.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We could foolproof this step by providing a zip file that had a sample themeset, ready to go.&amp;nbsp; You just run a &quot;run.sh&quot; or &quot;run.bat&quot; in the zip file&apos;s unpacked directory.&amp;nbsp; We could even include the curl and wget binaries for Windows.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This approach is a nice, small-step for the not-yet-committed.&amp;nbsp; How could we, though, make this process more productive for people that regularly theme?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We could write a Firefox extension that put a GUI on the operations and options, hiding the upload/download as background tasks.&amp;nbsp; This extension could start small: point at a themeset, a button to view the results, and links to the themed sample content.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over time, the extension could do more: show log messages about rule matches, provide a GUI to edit and validate the themeset file, make thumbnails, and upload to distribution servers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, those who are committed to Deliverance could use easy_installto grab the Deliverance themeset &quot;compiler&quot; itself, and not rely on a web service.&amp;nbsp; This would be a command-line tool that used lxml/libxml2 to generate the compiled themeset and package it up for distribution.We could also include a Paste-based local HTTP server that did theming on-the-fly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Distribute&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;A &quot;compiled themeset&quot; is a very, very simple package that can apply one or more look-and-feels to content based on some criteria.&amp;nbsp; It uses technology that is completely safe to distribute: no programming language, APIs, access to the filesystem, access to the web application, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Because they are safe and commodity, it makes sense to share them and pass them around.&amp;nbsp; We can have sites that provide hosting of themes,using a somewhat-smart themset server providing the following:&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;1) List packages.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2) Compile themesets.&amp;nbsp; This serves the purpose above, allowing themers to make themes without local software.&amp;nbsp; It also, though, provides some security check: rather than trust the themer&apos;s compiled result, make it on the server.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;3) Host versioned URLs to static theme resources.&amp;nbsp; Google recentlyannounced that they would provide stable URLs for important JavaScript resources.&amp;nbsp; Themeset servers could do the same for the images and CSS that go with a particular version of a theme.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With this, using a theme becomes even easier, as the static resources point to a stable, versioned URL that sets very long expires headers. In fact, we could leverage a free CDN such as Coral, without themers really having to understand it.&amp;nbsp; (And if the site manager didn&apos;t like it, they could run local versions.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;By doing so by default, we make such things easy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It would be tempting to have themeset servers that are just dumb static-file sites.&amp;nbsp; However, we should preserve the idea that the themeset server generates the compiled themeset, rather than trusting the theme makers.&amp;nbsp; Note that, rather than a full web application, you could still use Subversion with hooks that execute scripts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the workflow for a consulting project, you really don&apos;t think of putting the artifacts on a public site.&amp;nbsp; Thus, it should be easy and normal to run a private themeset server for a consulting project. (Alternatively, produce the themes and just put them in the buildout for the project, if the customer will never want to select new themes.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why zip files that aren&apos;t eggs?&amp;nbsp; Foremost, a themeset package isn&apos;t &quot;executable&quot;.&amp;nbsp; The process of installing a themeset shouldn&apos;t accidentally run some Python code.&amp;nbsp; We &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; leverage eggs, but that inherits quite a few contracts that might be stifling for the goal of&quot;easy&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Use&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;We now have lots of themeset packages available at various public and private themeset servers.&amp;nbsp; How can we radically improve how site managers leverage all this?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;First and foremost, make sure this part of the equation is dirt-simpleand reliable.&amp;nbsp; We can do so by moving most of the software complexity to the &quot;Make&quot; step: a compiled themeset is just an XSLT file plus some static resources and packaging artifacts.&amp;nbsp; All the work for parsing the theme(s) and the rules was already done in the compilation process.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next, we provide a web GUI for configuration.&amp;nbsp; This allows operations such as:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;simple&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Browse themeset servers to find and install new/updated themeset packages&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;List the currently installed themeset packages&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Change the active themeset to a different one&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Remove an installed themeset&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Where should this GUI be located?&amp;nbsp; It&apos;s natural for Plone to put thisin the &apos;site setup&quot; as a configlet.&amp;nbsp; There are reasons, though, thatthis might not be the only place to consider:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;simple&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Deliverance is about corporate identity across multiple sites and multiple systems.&amp;nbsp; It makes sense to centrally manage your themes from &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;outside&lt;/span&gt; a particular Plone site.&amp;nbsp; (OTOH, the people doing this might not want a GUI.)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;It is possible to have themeset configuration on a subsite basis.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are tons of opportunities here for fresh thinking about theme configuration, and most will prove easy to implement.&amp;nbsp; We should be open to new ideas on this aspect.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Summary&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Making, distributing, and using &quot;themes&quot; is an important cycle to look at for Plone&apos;s strategic planning.&amp;nbsp; Doing a superlative job at this part would make a deep impact on Plone&apos;s initial perception.&amp;nbsp; Doing this job in a &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;strategic&lt;/span&gt; way, where we think more about how Plone fits into the larger world for themers, integrators, and site managers, is worth discussion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>			<guid>http://radio.weblogs.com/0116506/2008/06/06.html#a455</guid>			<pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2008 15:18:38 GMT</pubDate>			<comments>http://radiocomments.userland.com/comments?u=116506&amp;amp;p=455&amp;amp;link=http%3A%2F%2Fradio.weblogs.com%2F0116506%2F2008%2F06%2F06.html%23a455</comments>			</item>		<item>			<title>Deliverance PSPS Update</title>			<link>http://radio.weblogs.com/0116506/2008/06/06.html#a454</link>			<description>I&apos;ve worked the last couple of days full-time on Deliverance:&lt;br&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Themeswitching Demo&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;I worked with Martin Aspeli, showing to use the new themeswitching features on the Deliverance trunk.&amp;nbsp; For this I made a &lt;a href=&quot;http://codespeak.net/svn/z3/deliverance/sandboxes/paul/environ/README.txt&quot;&gt;small tutorial&lt;/a&gt;. (I plan to re-do some of that tutorial, as I now understand more about WSGI filters.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;DVNG&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&apos;ve been talking on the Deliverance list about an experimental rewrite of Delivernace called &lt;a href=&quot;http://codespeak.net/svn/z3/deliverance/sandboxes/paul/dvng/README.txt&quot;&gt;DVNG&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the PSPS we solicited input on what was needed in Deliverance for Plone theming and Ian (with Wichert and others) came up with a proposed spec. This is an experiment in implementing those capabilities, along with an emphasis on: speed, reliability, debuggability, and extensibility.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;DVPlone&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since the PSPS is doing a follow-up at the symposium this week (e.g. today), I wanted to make a prototype of ideas on how &lt;a href=&quot;http://dev.plone.org/plone/ticket/7852&quot;&gt;my ticket&lt;/a&gt; might work.&amp;nbsp; Thus, I&apos;m pretty close on one approach to doing so and have a writeup that contemplates the big picture for theming.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m working on a writeup for this which I&apos;ll post later.&lt;/p&gt;</description>			<guid>http://radio.weblogs.com/0116506/2008/06/06.html#a454</guid>			<pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2008 14:12:50 GMT</pubDate>			<comments>http://radiocomments.userland.com/comments?u=116506&amp;amp;p=454&amp;amp;link=http%3A%2F%2Fradio.weblogs.com%2F0116506%2F2008%2F06%2F06.html%23a454</comments>			</item>		<item>			<title>Deliverance and Repoze talks at Plone Symposium</title>			<link>http://radio.weblogs.com/0116506/2008/03/10.html#a453</link>			<description>Tres and I are going to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://plone.org/events/regional/plone-symposium-2008/&quot;&gt;Plone Symposium&lt;/a&gt; at Penn State this week.I&apos;m giving &lt;a href=&quot;http://plone.org/events/regional/plone-symposium-2008/deliverance-humane-approaches-to-web-design-for-plone&quot;&gt;a talk on Deliverance&lt;/a&gt;, aimed at a designer and integrator (versus core developer) audience.  Tres is giving &lt;a href=&quot;http://plone.org/events/regional/plone-symposium-2008/integrating-python-web-apps-with-mod_wsgi-eggs-and-repoze&quot;&gt;a talk&lt;/a&gt; on how our Zope2/Plone world matches up to the Python web frameworks world. </description>			<guid>http://radio.weblogs.com/0116506/2008/03/10.html#a453</guid>			<pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2008 15:31:28 GMT</pubDate>			<comments>http://radiocomments.userland.com/comments?u=116506&amp;amp;p=453&amp;amp;link=http%3A%2F%2Fradio.weblogs.com%2F0116506%2F2008%2F03%2F10.html%23a453</comments>			</item>		<item>			<title>Virtual hosting and the ghetto</title>			<link>http://radio.weblogs.com/0116506/2008/03/10.html#a452</link>			<description>Chris &lt;a href=&quot;http://plope.com/Members/chrism/vhm_victory&quot;&gt;slays the VHM dragon&lt;/a&gt;.  The people contributing to &lt;a href=&quot;http://repoze.org/&quot;&gt;Repoze&lt;/a&gt; are helping to show the upside of WSGI and the benefits of &lt;a href=&quot;http://plope.com/Members/chrism/buildout_ghettoization&quot;&gt;getting out of our ghetto&lt;/a&gt;.Lotta stuff going on in Repoze land these days.</description>			<guid>http://radio.weblogs.com/0116506/2008/03/10.html#a452</guid>			<pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2008 15:28:01 GMT</pubDate>			<comments>http://radiocomments.userland.com/comments?u=116506&amp;amp;p=452&amp;amp;link=http%3A%2F%2Fradio.weblogs.com%2F0116506%2F2008%2F03%2F10.html%23a452</comments>			</item>		<item>			<title>Joel gets insanely great review</title>			<link>http://radio.weblogs.com/0116506/2008/03/10.html#a451</link>			<description>I just read a &lt;a href=&quot;http://destefano.wordpress.com/2008/03/10/training-review-plone-bootcamp/&quot;&gt;review&lt;/a&gt; of Joel Burton&apos;s Plone training.&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: 2em&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Despite its absurdly low cost, this course was the best open-source training I[base &apos;]ve ever taken, and among the best classes I[base &apos;]ve attended overall. The instructor possesses not only a mastery of the material, but he is also an excellent teacher, with a knack for drawing analogies to real-life experience, and interacting with and captivating the attention of large groups of students. I would not hesitate to recommend this class or others with this instructor. In fact, I would take the same class again, especially since I missed part of the five-day course. In addition, I would certainly be interested in more advanced courses taught by this instructor.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;While those sound like strong words, they sound right to me.  Joel is, indeed, insanely great at teaching.</description>			<guid>http://radio.weblogs.com/0116506/2008/03/10.html#a451</guid>			<pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2008 15:20:13 GMT</pubDate>			<comments>http://radiocomments.userland.com/comments?u=116506&amp;amp;p=451&amp;amp;link=http%3A%2F%2Fradio.weblogs.com%2F0116506%2F2008%2F03%2F10.html%23a451</comments>			</item>		<item>			<title>Plone-the-product vs. Plone-the-platform, Joel-on-software edition</title>			<link>http://radio.weblogs.com/0116506/2008/02/05.html#a450</link>			<description>This week Plone has a summit to discuss strategy.  For me, &quot;strategy&quot;means high-level kinds of questions like:  - What should Plone do well (vs. not worry about doing well)  - Who is it for (vs. not necessarily for)  - What makes it unique (vs. what things are commodity)  - Who are your natural competitorsUsing summit time to assess features for future releases is a goodidea.  But there should also be time to tackle strategy decisions thatinform feature planning.  I believe Jon is helping make that happen.In trying to help sort out such strategy questions, it&apos;s useful tomake a distinction between &quot;Plone-the-product&quot; and&quot;Plone-the-platform&quot; (aka the framework).The former is an out-of-the-box application with specificfunctionality for certain users.  That is, a specific user experience.The latter is UI-less set of capabilities from which you can go invarious directions to make your own products.  And each has a totally different set of answers to the questionsabove.  Stated differently, a totally different &quot;strategy&quot;.In trying to bring this up, I get either strong support or strongpushback.  The latter goes along the line of &quot;we&apos;re both&quot;, &quot;why limitourselves&quot;, and foremost, &quot;why does it matter&quot;.In this case, Joel Spolsky does a very admirable job &lt;ahref=&quot;http://www.joelonsoftware.com/articles/Platforms.html&quot;&gt;discussingplatforms&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left:2em;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&apos;s really, really important to figure out if your product is a platform or not, because platforms need to be marketed in a very different way to be successful. That&apos;s because a platform needs to appeal to developers first and foremost, not end users.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I just had the good fortune to read an advance copy of Rick Chapman&apos;s excellent new book on stupidity in the software industry...One of the biggest themes in software industry failures is a platform vendor that didn&apos;t understand that they were a platform vendor, so they alienated their key constituency: the developers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;Over the course of Zope&apos;s history, I&apos;ve watched this issue go throughseveral permutations.  The original Zope was a product that tried tohide, of all things, Python.  It then grew an extension concept(Products) for developers.The extension part was so popular that Python developers became thecore constituency.  Zope 3 mostly-abandoned the &quot;product&quot; side, whilestill sorta implying it would come up with backwards-compatibility tokeep those interests in the fold.  Instead, Zope 3 was aself-contained application server and platform.  And now, having &lt;ahref=&quot;http://plope.com/Members/chrism/le_roi_est_mort&quot;&gt;failed to gettraction&lt;/a&gt; as a self-contained universe, there is a final push tomake it assume its most natural place as a system of awesome,high-quality Python components.  (See &lt;ahref=&quot;http://plope.com/Members/chrism/le_roi_est_mort/talkback/1202110475&quot;&gt;Jens&apos;sresponse&lt;/a&gt; on &quot;The Zope Confusion&quot;.)I also think Mozilla is an example of not knowing if you&apos;re a productor a tool.  Three years ago, Mozilla was trying to make the bestbrowser on the planet.  Oh, and a great mail client.  And a greatcalendar.  And (of all freaking things) chat client.Oh, and it was also a platform of technologies (XUL, etc.) to writeextensions for said suite of stuff that went along with said browser.In fact, forget our products entirely...Mozilla is a platform forbuilding *anything*.People got woefully confused.  What exactly was Mozilla trying tosucceed at?  And so Mozilla re-branded: the browser became Firefox,the suite was sent to Siberia, the mail client was spun out, and thechat client was &quot;set free&quot;.  The word &quot;Mozilla&quot; meant platform.And that still wasn&apos;t enough focus.  The Mozilla Foundation finally,FINALLY made it clear whether their raison d&apos;etre was to make a killerbrowser or a generic internet technology.  They say that in theham-and-egg breakfast, the chicken is interested but the pig iscommitted.  MoFoCo said the browser *would* be excellent and theplaform *should* be excellent.  Big distinction.Using the word &quot;Plone&quot; to mean both the product and the platform is,IMO, the least attractive way forward.  It will never be clear topeople what, exactly, Plone is and isn&apos;t for.  What is it committed toexcellence on.  Who is its primary audience.  And finally, the reasonfor not choosing product-or-platform will become the ultimate &quot;house divided against itself&quot;outcome: people will think Plone components developed for the Ploneframework will only run in Plone.The good news is that Plone already runs on a framework.  In fact,several frameworks (Zope 2, CMF, Archetypes, Zope 3.)  Anoint one (orhelp invent one) as that which people should pay attention to, theninvest our activities under that flag, and make Plone a gorgeousassembly atop that other framework&apos;s genius.</description>			<guid>http://radio.weblogs.com/0116506/2008/02/05.html#a450</guid>			<pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2008 19:10:18 GMT</pubDate>			<comments>http://radiocomments.userland.com/comments?u=116506&amp;amp;p=450&amp;amp;link=http%3A%2F%2Fradio.weblogs.com%2F0116506%2F2008%2F02%2F05.html%23a450</comments>			</item>		<item>			<title>Nice meetup for last night&apos;s talk</title>			<link>http://radio.weblogs.com/0116506/2007/12/05.html#a449</link>			<description>I gave a talk last night at the ZPUG in DC.&amp;nbsp; In a nutshell, the talk was a gentle introduction to Paste and Deliverance.&amp;nbsp; Basically, I gave the kind of how-to-get-started that I would want to get, as a non-hardcore developer.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Turnout was good, but the atmosphere was even better.&amp;nbsp; &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Lots&lt;/span&gt; of discussions and questions at each step, frequently with the people discussing with each other.&amp;nbsp; There&apos;s a lot of interest in the topics of WSGI/eggs/Paste/middleware, and virtualenv/buildout/PyPI, and then how all the relates to particular frameworks like Zope and Plone.&amp;nbsp; My guess is that there is a pent-up demand for something like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.repoze.org/index.html&quot;&gt;Repoze&lt;/a&gt;, which tries to take all those things people think they should get started on, and make it Just Work in the Zope/Plone world.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;People really had some cool angles on how all this could shake out.&amp;nbsp; I really enjoyed the meeting.&amp;nbsp; Thanks to Alex Clark for organizing and Eric Coffman (and TNC) for hosting.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Regarding the material, I spent a bunch of time making progress on how to give a presentation and then have the material ready for good review afterwards.&amp;nbsp; Unfortunately, I still haven&apos;t found exactly the process that I&apos;m looking for, but got a lot closer.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Plus, I know a lot more about Paste now. [wink]&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Also in Repoze news, Chris and Tres had a talk last night in Chapel Hill, NC and one tonight in Charlotte, NC.&lt;br&gt;</description>			<guid>http://radio.weblogs.com/0116506/2007/12/05.html#a449</guid>			<pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2007 16:28:15 GMT</pubDate>			<comments>http://radiocomments.userland.com/comments?u=116506&amp;amp;p=449&amp;amp;link=http%3A%2F%2Fradio.weblogs.com%2F0116506%2F2007%2F12%2F05.html%23a449</comments>			</item>		<item>			<title>Talking about Deliverance next week in DC</title>			<link>http://radio.weblogs.com/0116506/2007/11/30.html#a448</link>			<description>Next  week I&apos;m &lt;a href=&quot;http://zpugdc.org/meetings/mtg58&quot;&gt;giving a talk&lt;/a&gt; in Washington DC on Tuesday, Dec 4 to the Zope/Python Users Group (ZPUG) DC.I&apos;ll be talking about Repoze from a middleware perspective.  Specifically, I&apos;ll talk about using Deliverance to apply a single corporate identity to all Python web applications.  I&apos;ll also try to give a beginner&apos;s guide to using Paste as a quick way to get a sandbox going.If you&apos;re interested in Python web technologies, but aren&apos;t a guru, this would probably be a decent meeting to attend.  Hopefully we can talk a little bit about the people that put user interfaces, navigation, and other non-core-development value into a project, and find out more about how to fit their needs.</description>			<guid>http://radio.weblogs.com/0116506/2007/11/30.html#a448</guid>			<pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2007 19:52:47 GMT</pubDate>			<comments>http://radiocomments.userland.com/comments?u=116506&amp;amp;p=448&amp;amp;link=http%3A%2F%2Fradio.weblogs.com%2F0116506%2F2007%2F11%2F30.html%23a448</comments>			</item>		<item>			<title>New ideas regarding page composition</title>			<link>http://radio.weblogs.com/0116506/2007/11/07.html#a447</link>			<description>The prodigious Carlos de la Guardia wrote an intriguing article about &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.delaguardia.com.mx/index.php?op=ViewArticle&amp;amp;articleId=88&amp;amp;blogId=1&quot;&gt;Plone Performance and the Future of ZPT&lt;/a&gt;. He poses a question in the article: &quot;I wonder if Deliverance could be useful here also?&quot;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Short answer: yes. Longer answer: sorta, and I&apos;d like to find out what people think. So read on, and if you have an interest in alternative thinking on how HTML UIs get generated, ping me.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;As background, before I used the word &quot;Deliverance&quot;, I was focusing only on &lt;a href=&quot;http://wiki.zope.org/zope3/SiteThemes&quot;&gt;Zope Site Themes&lt;/a&gt;.  I view theming as distinct from skinning.  A theme is only about corporate identity.  There isn&apos;t really any computation, iteration, or any programmer-oriented stuff.  Instead, you&apos;re just re-arranging HTML. You are probably leveraging existing artifacts.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I then got interested in &lt;a href=&quot;http://lists.nuxeo.com/pipermail/z3lab/2005-May/000172.html&quot;&gt;splitting content management from content delivery&lt;/a&gt; and wanted a project that did both theming and composition.  And I thought &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0068473/&quot;&gt;Deliverance&lt;/a&gt; was a hilarious name.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I keep vacillating, though, on whether one facility should do both.  I still change my mind constantly on this.  On one hand, I think they are very distinct audiences (site designers and templating integrators.)  In the new, Repoze-oriented world of middleware, that would mean:&lt;br&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;A WSGI middleware step takes the CMS output (likely semantic markup) and does &quot;templating&quot; to generate an HTML UI&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The next middleware step (Deliverance) takes the mostly-done HTML and applies a corporate ID.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;On the other hand, people might want it to be conceptually part of one step.  For example, Ian said I should start by using the XSLT version of Deliverance and just having some custom rules that do the first step. It certainly would shave off some performance penalty you&apos;d get by converting a tree to a string and back into a tree between middleware steps.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;My instinct says that isolation, though, is better.  I&apos;ll probably start on that path.  (Tres gave me pointers on how to approach it.)&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;As &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openplans.org/projects/plone-performance-sprint-2007/alan-runyan-offered-some-nice-ideas-and-insight-as-well&quot;&gt;Alan mentioned&lt;/a&gt; in a link from Carlos&apos;s article:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Enfold is working on xslt and doing page assembly outside of zope (in apache or IIS) using enfold.lxml (in our public repository).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br&gt;I worked with Enfold on this for two very large projects, one of which (Open Society Institute&apos;s KARL system) was the keynote at the Plone Conference. In this, Plone generates an XML string for the information needed on a page.  Something outside Plone takes that and generates a UI.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;This has some interesting and positive performance implications.  More importantly, it had a big consulting process impact.  We were able to model every screen in the system as an XML file on disk.  We then refined the UI with the customer, using templates (in our case XSLT) that didn&apos;t require a server or framework. Meaning, the customer could hack on it without screwing up &quot;the server&quot;.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Since these same templates were used in production, there wasn&apos;t really a mockup stage. As long as the &quot;back end&quot; generated the same XML structure our dummy files expected, everything Just Worked.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Forget for a moment whether this uses XML/XSLT or JSON/Genshi or EBCDIC/Cobal.&amp;nbsp; Let&apos;s isolate the concept itself (moving HTML UI generation out of the framework) and see if there is interest.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I&apos;d like to discuss using WSGI middleware for page composition and theming to achieve the following goals:&lt;br&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Separate the generation of the information (Plone) from the generation of a custom HTML UI&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Increase performance by (insert a few reasons here)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Allow integrators to make more meaningful customizations without learning a component framework&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Use schemas to increase quality by bringing a unit-test-like approach to the UI stage&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;If you&apos;re interested, let me know.  I can start with a series of screencasts (and yes, Geir, writeups) that try to show what&apos;s been done and why it might be worth discussing, if there is interest.&lt;br&gt;</description>			<guid>http://radio.weblogs.com/0116506/2007/11/07.html#a447</guid>			<pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2007 15:52:01 GMT</pubDate>			<comments>http://radiocomments.userland.com/comments?u=116506&amp;amp;p=447&amp;amp;link=http%3A%2F%2Fradio.weblogs.com%2F0116506%2F2007%2F11%2F07.html%23a447</comments>			</item>		<item>			<title>Repoze at ZPUG last night</title>			<link>http://radio.weblogs.com/0116506/2007/11/07.html#a446</link>			<description>Last night &lt;a href=&quot;http://plope.com/&quot;&gt;Chris McDonough&lt;/a&gt; gave &lt;a href=&quot;http://zpugdc.org/meetings/mtg57&quot;&gt;a presentation&lt;/a&gt; to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://zpugdc.org/&quot;&gt;Zope/Python User Group&lt;/a&gt; of Washington, D.C.&amp;nbsp; I went along for the festivities and quite enjoyed myself.&amp;nbsp; Pretty good turnout.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;As preparation, Chris wrote a &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.repoze.org/devwrepoze-zope2-pdf.html&quot;&gt;detailed article&lt;/a&gt; about getting started with Repoze:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;We&apos;ve just created and released Developing With repoze.zope2 which is a short 10-page PDF that explains the benefits of and differences between developing Zope 2 applications using Repoze and &quot;stock&quot; Zope 2. It might be helpful to folks developing under Plone and CMF.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br&gt;I believe we&apos;re slated to give another talk at the next ZPUG meeting in December.&amp;nbsp; I might give a walkthrough on using &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openplans.org/projects/deliverance&quot;&gt;Deliverance&lt;/a&gt; to theme your Plone site.&amp;nbsp; I&apos;ll probably just play my &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.repoze.org/setting-up-deliverance-screencast-20071025.html&quot;&gt;screencast&lt;/a&gt; and claim I put effort into preparation. [wink]&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;We&apos;re also interested in getting Repoze more out and into the wild.&amp;nbsp; First, we&apos;re talking with Plone/Zope/Python user groups on the east coast, seeing if we can get our travel covered to come give more talks on WSGI and Repoze.&amp;nbsp; If you&apos;re interested and can cover our travel, drop us a line.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;We also want to get more folks into Repoze, so it&apos;s bigger than us.&amp;nbsp; Both people that want to contribute, but also, people that want to start using it for real.&amp;nbsp; Drop by #repoze on irc.freenode.net and hang out with us.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;</description>			<guid>http://radio.weblogs.com/0116506/2007/11/07.html#a446</guid>			<pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2007 14:52:28 GMT</pubDate>			<comments>http://radiocomments.userland.com/comments?u=116506&amp;amp;p=446&amp;amp;link=http%3A%2F%2Fradio.weblogs.com%2F0116506%2F2007%2F11%2F07.html%23a446</comments>			</item>		<item>			<title>Might we be returning to a One True Zope?</title>			<link>http://radio.weblogs.com/0116506/2007/11/07.html#a445</link>			<description>When you say &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zope.org/&quot;&gt;Zope&lt;/a&gt; to someone, they may or may not hear the same thing you said.&amp;nbsp; There&apos;s Zope 2.&amp;nbsp; There&apos;s a completely different thing called Zope 3.&amp;nbsp; There&apos;s also a company, but that&apos;s a different topic.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;It&apos;s thus with great relief this morning to read Baiju&apos;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://baijum81.livejournal.com/24017.html&quot;&gt;At last Zope 3 releases coming to an end !&lt;/a&gt; post.&amp;nbsp; It&apos;s somewhat startling, and exciting, to hear this said in public:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;I won&apos;t be surprised if the term &quot;Zope 3&quot; itself vanish in the future.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br&gt;I realize there is a small contingent that wants their Zope 3 isolated from Zope 2, never to even touch each other.&amp;nbsp; Honestly, if that was the outcome you wanted, why even call the rewrite &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zope.org/&quot;&gt;Zope&lt;/a&gt; in the first place?&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Next discussion, hopefully, will be whether that one Zope is an application server or a framework, or some other jargon that doesn&apos;t mean &quot;closed world platform&quot;. [wink]&lt;br&gt;</description>			<guid>http://radio.weblogs.com/0116506/2007/11/07.html#a445</guid>			<pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2007 14:40:43 GMT</pubDate>			<comments>http://radiocomments.userland.com/comments?u=116506&amp;amp;p=445&amp;amp;link=http%3A%2F%2Fradio.weblogs.com%2F0116506%2F2007%2F11%2F07.html%23a445</comments>			</item>		<item>			<title>Plone events on the horizon</title>			<link>http://radio.weblogs.com/0116506/2007/10/28.html#a444</link>			<description>The Plone community manages the selection on its Plone Conference each year as the one big event that brings us together.&amp;nbsp; I believe there is also a sense, though, that we should encourage a number of smaller, regional events as well.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;There are two planned that I know about.&amp;nbsp; Mike Halm is planning an event at Penn State University, March 10-15.&amp;nbsp; The event is called &quot;Rally in the Valley: Setting Directions for Higher Education&quot;.&amp;nbsp; I believe they&apos;re looking to have really good turnout.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Enfold is planning to have its famous Plone Symposium in New Orleans, June 4-6, same venue as last time.&amp;nbsp; Focus is on Plone development and consulting.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Expect announcements on both of these in the coming weeks.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I believe there is also talk about having a Zope/Plone event in Brazil in conjunction with FISL.&amp;nbsp; Anybody else planning anything?&lt;br&gt;</description>			<guid>http://radio.weblogs.com/0116506/2007/10/28.html#a444</guid>			<pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2007 17:02:55 GMT</pubDate>			<comments>http://radiocomments.userland.com/comments?u=116506&amp;amp;p=444&amp;amp;link=http%3A%2F%2Fradio.weblogs.com%2F0116506%2F2007%2F10%2F28.html%23a444</comments>			</item>		<item>			<title>Thanks Pilot Systems for working on Plone.net</title>			<link>http://radio.weblogs.com/0116506/2007/10/27.html#a443</link>			<description>Today I spent some time going through the review queue on &lt;a href=&quot;http://plone.net/&quot;&gt;Plone.net&lt;/a&gt;. Current status: 209 &lt;a href=&quot;http://plone.net/providers/&quot;&gt;providers&lt;/a&gt; in 44 countries, 896 &lt;a href=&quot;http://plone.net/sites/&quot;&gt;sites&lt;/a&gt; listed, 23 &lt;a href=&quot;http://plone.net/case-studies/&quot;&gt;case studies&lt;/a&gt;, and even 20 &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://plone.net/buzz/&quot;&gt;in the media&lt;/a&gt;&quot; listings.&amp;nbsp; Moreover, the submission rate seems to be picking up.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Which leads to one of the biggest reasons Plone.net is getting traction: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pilotsystems.net/&quot;&gt;Pilot Systems&lt;/a&gt; (Plone.net &lt;a href=&quot;http://plone.net/providers/pilot&quot;&gt;entry&lt;/a&gt;).&amp;nbsp; The Plone.net team has a good number of contributors, but Pilot Systems (David Sapiro and Ga&amp;euml;l Le Mignot) are the real reasons that sustained energy over time has continued.&amp;nbsp; Not only have the already done a lot, but they&apos;d do even more if Paulie the Lazybutt would pitch in and organize the Trac issues.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Thanks Pilot guys for making Plone.net a success.&lt;br&gt;</description>			<guid>http://radio.weblogs.com/0116506/2007/10/27.html#a443</guid>			<pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2007 16:13:54 GMT</pubDate>			<comments>http://radiocomments.userland.com/comments?u=116506&amp;amp;p=443&amp;amp;link=http%3A%2F%2Fradio.weblogs.com%2F0116506%2F2007%2F10%2F27.html%23a443</comments>			</item>		</channel>	</rss>