<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<rdf:RDF xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
         xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" 
         xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
         xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">

<channel rdf:about="http://base-art.net">
<description>Phil's blog</description>
<link>http://base-art.net</link>
<title>Base-Art / Articles</title>



<items>
<rdf:seq>

<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://base-art.net/Articles/102/"/>

<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://base-art.net/Articles/101/"/>

<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://base-art.net/Articles/100/"/>

<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://base-art.net/Articles/99/"/>

<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://base-art.net/Articles/98/"/>

<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://base-art.net/Articles/97/"/>

<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://base-art.net/Articles/96/"/>

<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://base-art.net/Articles/95/"/>

<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://base-art.net/Articles/94/"/>

<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://base-art.net/Articles/93/"/>

</rdf:seq>
</items>


</channel>





<item rdf:about="http://base-art.net/Articles/102/">
<dc:date>2008-05-21T20:07:49.000002+02:00</dc:date>
<title>GUADEC</title>
<link>http://base-art.net/Articles/102/</link>
<author>Philippe Normand</author>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;Anyone going to &lt;a class="reference" href="http://2008.guadec.es/guadec"&gt;GUADEC-ES&lt;/a&gt;? I can't go to GUADEC this year for various reasons... Living in Spain, I'm wondering about GUADEC-ES ;) Might be worth the trip to Madrid, which I haven't visited yet. Maybe the occasion to do a little lightning talk about &lt;a class="reference" href="http://elisa.fluendo.com"&gt;Elisa&lt;/a&gt; too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;update&lt;/strong&gt;: holiday not granted by boss, I'm pissed. :(&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
</item>


<item rdf:about="http://base-art.net/Articles/101/">
<dc:date>2008-05-09T17:36:22.000004+02:00</dc:date>
<title>Elisa on Windows and new resources for contributors</title>
<link>http://base-art.net/Articles/101/</link>
<author>Philippe Normand</author>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;So our Windows developer strike force came up with a windows version
of &lt;a class="reference" href="http://elisa.fluendo.com"&gt;Elisa&lt;/a&gt;, Windows XP and Vista are supported. Check out the &lt;cite&gt;Elisa
download&lt;/cite&gt; page to find the alpha version of the installer. There are
some issues, this is an alpha, you're warned :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alessandro and Olivier cooked 2 &lt;a class="reference" href="http://elisa.fluendo.com/documentation/tutorials/"&gt;tutorials&lt;/a&gt; showing off how to develop
new features for Elisa, by example. The &lt;a class="reference" href="http://elisa.fluendo.com/api"&gt;API&lt;/a&gt; of the upcoming 0.5
branch of Elisa has also been published, it might evolve a bit but
it's already a good starting point for motivated contributors out
there :)&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
</item>


<item rdf:about="http://base-art.net/Articles/100/">
<dc:date>2008-05-05T17:14:08+02:00</dc:date>
<title>On-going projects status report</title>
<link>http://base-art.net/Articles/100/</link>
<author>Philippe Normand</author>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;Last time I blogged about &lt;a class="reference" href="http://elisa.fluendo.com"&gt;Elisa&lt;/a&gt; was end of February in an ultimate
attempt to keep up with the weekly news reporting idea. I miserably
failed since then... Some people recently asked me some status on
Elisa, so I'll do my best to deliver some periodic insider news of
&lt;a class="reference" href="http://elisa.fluendo.com"&gt;Elisa&lt;/a&gt; and the other projects I'm involved on ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;March was the month of the Elisa &lt;a class="reference" href="http://elisa.fluendo.com/2008/04/02/new-tools-for-the-elisa-community/"&gt;organization changes&lt;/a&gt;, the
bug tracker is slowly moving towards Launchpad, the code was moved to
Bazaar branches (about 20 so far) and the code reviews process was
officialized (mailing list and BundleBuggy). All these changes are
meant to ease contributions to the project and increase its visibility
in the FOSS world, we'll see how it goes :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team significantly grew up, we have 2 new developers working on
the windows ports of both Pigment and Elisa, one QA manager working on
improving the global quality assessment of the code we write and a new
graphic designer, smashing his head on the UI ergonomy and look. This
is quite amazing, at some point we needed a sheet of paper with names and assigned roles on the wall to keep up with new people arrivals!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the whole team is mainly working on the upcoming 0.5 branch of
Elisa, for which a first release is scheduled in june. Many
architecture changes on the table, a revisited UI framework, some new
plugins to drive more content to the end-user and the usual
fixes. More details to come later about that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some news about &lt;a class="reference" href="https://code.fluendo.com/pigment/trac"&gt;Pigment&lt;/a&gt;, Loïc worked on the OpenGL|ES plugin and
support for touchscreens. This opens up Pigment to a wide range of
embedded platforms! The plan is to release a 0.4 version soon. Work is
heading towards the Pigment 0.5 branch. Guillaume is continuing
his efforts on the &lt;a class="reference" href="http://live.gnome.org/PAF"&gt;PAF&lt;/a&gt; animation framework, the API is coming along
nicely, let's keep an eye on this promising project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last but not least both Pigment and Elisa will be presented at next &lt;a class="reference" href="http://guadec.org"&gt;GUADEC&lt;/a&gt;, be sure to attend!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
</item>


<item rdf:about="http://base-art.net/Articles/99/">
<dc:date>2008-05-03T17:15:38.000005+02:00</dc:date>
<title>Coherence strikes back</title>
<link>http://base-art.net/Articles/99/</link>
<author>Philippe Normand</author>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;With a release per month, &lt;a class="reference" href="https://coherence.beebits.net/"&gt;Coherence&lt;/a&gt; is evolving rapidly, the
community is coming along, it's nice to see the IRC channel filling up
with developers and users. Recently Frank added a backend for
&lt;a class="reference" href="http://www.gnome.org/projects/tracker/index.html"&gt;Tracker&lt;/a&gt;, it's a bit rough on the edges currently and publishes only
the Music files over UPnP, but support for Videos and Pictures
publishing will come soon! In the future, every media file you'll have
on your desktop monitored by Tracker will be potentially available to
the other devices of your living network via UPnP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One nice use-case is to use Rhythmbox on one computer to play the
media hosted on another desktop, transparently, with no headaches of
setting up a network share. Work is currently being done towards a
desktop applet called &lt;a class="reference" href="http://29a.ch/gcoherence/"&gt;gcoherence&lt;/a&gt; meant to ease the configuration and
setup of Coherence:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class="reference image-reference" href="http://29a.ch/gcoherence/"&gt;&lt;img alt="http://base-art.net/static/gcoherence.png" src="http://base-art.net/static/gcoherence.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another new feature of Coherence is a MediaServer backend for
&lt;a class="reference" href="http://www.ampache.org/"&gt;Ampache&lt;/a&gt;, a web-based audio jukebox system. I haven't tested that one
yet, but Ampache looks like a nice toy to play with in the near future
:)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great stuff guys, keep up the good work :)&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
</item>


<item rdf:about="http://base-art.net/Articles/98/">
<dc:date>2008-03-12T23:22:48.000002+02:00</dc:date>
<title>Releases!</title>
<link>http://base-art.net/Articles/98/</link>
<author>Philippe Normand</author>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;Yeah &lt;a class="reference" href="http://gnome.org"&gt;GNOME&lt;/a&gt; 2.22 is out! Yeah &lt;a class="reference" href="http://elisa.fluendo.com/2008/03/12/elisa-new-releases/"&gt;Elisa 0.3.5 is out&lt;/a&gt; ! Let's
celebrate :) Well it still has no DVB, no standard DVD, no
HD-DVD (it's dead anyway), no Blue-ray support BUT 0.3.5 brings
drag&amp;amp;drop, a little nice splash screen, Codeina (or CodecBuddy,
or whatever its name now), some UI improvements and the usual
bugfixes. I really think we're on the right track, the software
is slowly but surely getting mature, people actually write Elisa
plugins, translate Elisa in their language and help us to hunt
bugs, this is cool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference" href="http://lists.fluendo.com/pipermail/pigment/2008-March/000009.html"&gt;Pigment 0.3.5&lt;/a&gt; was recently released too. Loïc and Guillaume
are now starting to work on the &lt;a class="reference" href="https://guij.emont.org/blog/2008/03/11/future-of-pigment/"&gt;future Pigment&lt;/a&gt; and they have
already ambitious great plans, good stuff to come for sure, let's
keep an eye on how it will evolve :) I'm especially looking
forward the &lt;a class="reference" href="https://guij.emont.org/blog/2008/03/10/paf-animation-framework/"&gt;Paf! animation framework&lt;/a&gt;, let's stop reinventing
the animation framework wheel now, we need a generic animation
framework, be sure to read Guillaume's post, it's very
interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
</item>


<item rdf:about="http://base-art.net/Articles/97/">
<dc:date>2008-02-27T22:49:37.000002+02:00</dc:date>
<title>Hi Planet GNOME!</title>
<link>http://base-art.net/Articles/97/</link>
<author>Philippe Normand</author>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;Just a quick post to say hi to the &lt;a class="reference" href="http://planet.gnome.org"&gt;GNOME community&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks Jeff for adding me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I'm Philippe (philn on IRC), working for Fluendo on the &lt;a class="reference" href="http://elisa.fluendo.com"&gt;Elisa&lt;/a&gt;
MediaCenter, writing Python fluently during work hours for fun and
profit and off work, only for fun :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I regularly write news about &lt;a class="reference" href="http://elisa.fluendo.com"&gt;Elisa&lt;/a&gt;, did some posts about &lt;a class="reference" href="https://code.fluendo.com/pigment/trac/timeline"&gt;Pigment&lt;/a&gt;
and &lt;a class="reference" href="http://gstreamer.freedesktop.org"&gt;GStreamer&lt;/a&gt; too and a good bunch of posts related to various
hacks and ramblings about Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So expect new posts about Pigment and Elisa towards better
integration in the GNOME desktop. I'll also try to blog about my
little growing experience in the GStreamer world :)&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
</item>


<item rdf:about="http://base-art.net/Articles/96/">
<dc:date>2008-02-21T12:57:33.000003+02:00</dc:date>
<title>Elisa weekly (not that weekly) news #6</title>
<link>http://base-art.net/Articles/96/</link>
<author>Philippe Normand</author>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;Hey been a while since last shot of Elisa news... Be not
disapointed, much is happening! Let's see...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole team is firing up to cook an Elisa release candidate
for tomorrow and final release should happen end of next
week. What's new? The plugin management framework entered test
stage, the server is coming along nicely and the client library
became more robust thanks to Guido's continuous
efforts. Integration in Elisa UI has been started. Elisa will
check every hour for updates from the server and manage its
plugin upgrades automagically with minimum user
interaction. Benjamin has been working on drag&amp;amp;drop
support (which was added in Pigment by Loïc). So we can now
easily add new media locations in Elisa by &amp;quot;putting&amp;quot; them in the
Elisa window, sweet :) Same goes for plugins, if you download
some Egg files providing Elisa plugins and drag them to the Elisa
window, they will be installed too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Benjamin also worked on a benchmarking process. First time Elisa
is launched a Pigment benchmark is started to see how fast the
user machine is, if it handles the various OpenGL things Pigment
supports. This is useful to warn the user if Elisa won't be able
to run smoothly on his machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Florian brought a shiny new Slideshow plugin to Elisa, code is
much cleaner and bugless this time, which is good news. He also fixed
a good bunch of bugs in the frontend code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alessandro worked on &lt;a class="reference" href="http://fedoraproject.org/wiki/Multimedia/Codeina"&gt;Codeina&lt;/a&gt; (or CodecBuddy, or whatever its
name) support for Elisa. It means that if Elisa isn't able to
play a file because a codec is missing then a little program
fires up and handles additional codecs installation, mostly
without user interaction. In the future versions of Elisa we'll
have deeper integration with Codeina and the codec installation
UI will be managed by Elisa itself. Now Alessandro is busy
preparing his FOSDEM talk, I cross fingers for you dude :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Loïc is also preparing his talk for FOSDEM. He has been working
on an impressive little application to show Pigment bling and
play with mapping matrices and a webcam. I shall tell no more,
be at FOSDEM this weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guillaume has been thinking about Pigment 0.5 and more
specifically the rewrite of our current Python animation
framework in C. He's investigating on the current solutions
available to compare them... See his work on the &lt;a class="reference" href="https://code.fluendo.com/pigment/trac/wiki/ExistingTimingFrameworks"&gt;wiki&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
</item>


<item rdf:about="http://base-art.net/Articles/95/">
<dc:date>2008-02-12T22:17:45.000001+02:00</dc:date>
<title>N810: first impressions</title>
<link>http://base-art.net/Articles/95/</link>
<author>Philippe Normand</author>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;Two weeks ago I bought my N810 with the discount code kindly
offered by Nokia for the Maemo development program. The device is
really nice, the OS2008 provides a totally new user
experience (compared to the version I used on my N770). So here
are few remarks I have after few weeks of usage:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the padlock slider is too easy to activate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the keyboard is coool but I sometimes have difficulties with
the keys of the first row in the keyboard. To me they are
slightly too near from the screen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I dislike the kinda &amp;quot;micro&amp;quot; USB plug, it looks like some Nokia
specific plug, a mini-usb plug would have been more handy so
that I could use the same USB wire as for my camera.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far I used the IM a bit with Frank for a video chat and with
Mom for an audio-only GoogleTalk chat. Sound is good but video
quality was bad, I need to make more tests I guess :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Played a bit with MediaStreamer and &lt;a class="reference" href="https://coherence.beebits.net/"&gt;Coherence&lt;/a&gt;, everything works
fine, excepted seeking that's lacking because Coherence HTTP
server doesn't yet support HTTP range requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also did some media transcoding so that I can watch videos on
the device. Videos need to be encoded in MP4 at some specific
resolutions. Fortunately there's an &lt;a class="reference" href="http://mediautils.garage.maemo.org/tablet-encode.html"&gt;handy script&lt;/a&gt; at maemo.org to
do the whole job for me :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last weekend I gave a try to geottagging using the &lt;a class="reference" href="http://maemo.org/community/wiki/HowToUseGPSFrameworkInOS2007"&gt;documentation on
Maemo wiki&lt;/a&gt;. I ended up with a nice KML file that can be displayed on
Google Earth and &lt;a class="reference" href="http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;amp;hl=fr&amp;amp;geocode=&amp;amp;q=http:%2F%2Fbase-art.net%2Fstatic%2Ftest.kml&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;z=14&amp;amp;om=0"&gt;Google Maps&lt;/a&gt; (see below too). I'll directly
integrate these features in my gallery soon, geotagging is an
interesting thing, especially for my next holidays... :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="300" height="300" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" src="http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;hl=fr&amp;geocode=&amp;q=http:%2F%2Fbase-art.net%2Fstatic%2Ftest.kml&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;om=0&amp;s=AARTsJoKslGlhTBznoJVAptgAtiDnwEaVg&amp;ll=41.390138,2.18844&amp;spn=0.045075,0.072956&amp;z=13&amp;output=embed"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;hl=fr&amp;geocode=&amp;q=http:%2F%2Fbase-art.net%2Fstatic%2Ftest.kml&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;om=0&amp;ll=41.390138,2.18844&amp;spn=0.045075,0.072956&amp;z=13&amp;source=embed" style="color:#0000FF;text-align:left"&gt;Agrandir le plan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the coming weeks I'll start developing user-interfaces using the
Python EFL libraries. I'll most likely play a bit with the Coherence
MediaRenderer called &lt;a class="reference" href="https://coherence.beebits.net/wiki/CoherenceMediaRenderer"&gt;Compere&lt;/a&gt;, so far implemented using PyGame and try
to rework it with the EFL libs... More to come later :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;edit&lt;/strong&gt;: Frank the Coherence guru reminds me that Coherence de facto supports HTTP range requests but MediaStreamer HTTP client doesn't implement the seek requests correctly... :)&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
</item>


<item rdf:about="http://base-art.net/Articles/94/">
<dc:date>2008-01-30T23:15:00.000002+02:00</dc:date>
<title>Coherence and Rhythmbox love</title>
<link>http://base-art.net/Articles/94/</link>
<author>Philippe Normand</author>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;Some heads up and bling on &lt;a class="reference" href="https://coherence.beebits.net"&gt;Coherence&lt;/a&gt; front. Rhythmbox now acts as MediaServer, MediaClient and MediaRenderer thanks to Frank's great efforts. This is awesome :) See the demo video, it really blows you away:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;object width="425" height="355"&gt;&lt;param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/N4dY2ByvOsU&amp;rel=1"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name="wmode" value="transparent"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/N4dY2ByvOsU&amp;rel=1" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" wmode="transparent" width="425" height="355"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;p&gt;And the Rhythmbox plugin is developed in Python&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
</item>


<item rdf:about="http://base-art.net/Articles/93/">
<dc:date>2008-01-29T11:54:04.000001+02:00</dc:date>
<title>Elisa weekly news #5</title>
<link>http://base-art.net/Articles/93/</link>
<author>Philippe Normand</author>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to this new edition of &lt;a class="reference" href="http://elisa.fluendo.com"&gt;Elisa&lt;/a&gt; weekly news. I'm not very
regular on the timetable, but yet haven't reached the 3-weeks
limit! :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what happened since last week? First off we've got Huge
feedback from the release, good press coverage so far, especially
an article on &lt;a class="reference" href="http://arstechnica.com/journals/linux.ars/2008/01/22/elisa-0-3-3-turns-linux-into-a-movie-theater"&gt;ars technica&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;a class="reference" href="http://elisa.fluendo.com"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; is having trouble to
keep up with the hits, we'll soon move it to a new
server. Enthousiasts (or desperate, it depends) users keep
flowing on the IRC channel at any time, this is exciting! Many
thanks to Saviq, dev, hugolp and some others who form the first
non-core-elisa support team. Many things happen on IRC, someone
is building an Elisa live CD, another one did a plugin to list
MythTV recordings and watch live-TV from the Myth backend. It's
really nice for us to see people having fun with Elisa like we do
every day at work :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the development side, Benjamin and Florian are designing a new
API to replace the current media_provider API and improve the MVC
framework to go even further in the modularization process. This
new move is inspired from the REST architecture of the Web, among
other things. I'm working with Guido on the Plugin Repository
framework, we've got a (console) client/server prototype so far,
it's coming along nicely and will very soon be integrated in the
Elisa UI. Alessandro is doing some GStreamer development, hunting
some bugs either in gst-python or directly in the GStreamer
plugins. In the end we are getting some nice improvements inside
Elisa :) He will also move the Elisa media_scanner in a separate
plugin, out of the core.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Loïc released Pigment 0.3.4 and Pigment-python 0.3.2 last
week. He also added ARGB support to the Pigment OpenGL plugin,
meaning that we are now able to make even more bling inside
Elisa, like apply color masks to drawables. He also added some
API to hide/show the Viewport. Next he'll work on freedesktop
startup specification support and minimize/maximize the viewport
in the tray bar, everything towards better Pigment integration in
the desktop! Guillaume is hunting an annoying race condition
inside X.org's XCB library which makes Pigment based applications
crash on some distributions like Fedora8.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
</item>



</rdf:RDF>