<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.blogger.com/styles/atom.css" type="text/css"?><feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom' xmlns:openSearch='http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/'><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-1844829803862335252</id><updated>2008-06-03T17:04:54.256-04:00</updated><title type='text'>MySQL-Python</title><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://mysql-python.blogspot.com/'/><link rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://mysql-python.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://mysql-python.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default'/><author><name>Andy Dustman</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/13581204403076051529</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email></author><generator version='7.00' uri='http://www.blogger.com'>Blogger</generator><openSearch:totalResults>9</openSearch:totalResults><openSearch:startIndex>1</openSearch:startIndex><openSearch:itemsPerPage>25</openSearch:itemsPerPage><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-1844829803862335252.post-6076924685321497970</id><published>2008-05-14T23:27:00.002-04:00</published><updated>2008-05-14T23:31:14.504-04:00</updated><category scheme='http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#' term='mysql python nagios cacti zenoss syslog monitoring'/><title type='text'>Zenoss Deathmatch</title><content type='html'>&lt;div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"&gt;I've been working for the last week on implementing Zenoss to replace &lt;a href="http://www.nagios.org/"&gt;Nagios&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.cacti.net/"&gt;Cacti&lt;/a&gt;. Individually Nagios and Cacti are pretty good at what they do, but they don't integrate well.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Nagios is primarily an availability monitor, so it's good for notifying you when something goes down, or a disk is filling up, or the load average is too high. etc., but it's not so great for monitoring performance. Nagios 1.4 uses text configuration files. There is a templating system which can be helpful if you have a lot of identical systems.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Cacti, on the other hand, is pretty good at monitoring performance, as in how much bandwidth are you using, resource utilization, and so on with nice long-term graphs using &lt;a href="http://oss.oetiker.ch/rrdtool/"&gt;RRDtool&lt;/a&gt;, but it's not so great for notifying if something is down. Cacti is almost exclusively SNMP-based, and as a result, you can usually just point it at a device through the web interface and it will auto-discover everything interesting. If you have more than a few hundred items to measure, you need to use &lt;a href="http://www.cacti.net/cactid_info.php"&gt;cactid&lt;/a&gt;, which is a very fast threaded poller written in C.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I've been using both for about 3-4 years separately, but because they don't integrate easily (even though both use MySQL as their backend storage), there's a lot of duplication of effort in getting both of them configured.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And then there's Zenoss. Zenoss does both availablity and performance monitoring, with long-term graphing using RRDtool, log analysis, and network-based auto-discovery. Zenoss is written in Python using the Zope-2 framework.  Most of the device metadata is stored on ZODB, Zope's native object database. Long-term performance data is stored in RRDtool. Event logs are stored in MySQL.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Everything in Zenoss integrates together very well. The data is faceted in the sense that you can browse devices by location, by class, by group, or by system. It has a built-in syslog server, it can use WMI for monitoring Windows systems, it has very flexible event handling.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There are still some rough edges in 2.1.92, which is a beta for 2.2. First is, it's a bit of a memory hog and I'm inclined to believe there are some memory leaks. After a day or two the main process will start to use over 200 MB; restarting tends to knock it back down to to around 100 MB or so.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Syslog support has some issues. When I first started feeding it some syslog data, all the events were being classified as "/Unknown". This is normal. Once you have some log entires, you can then tell it to map that entry to an event. The problem was, the events had components (the process name when parsing syslog data), but they had no event classes set. Looking at the code, it seemed like it should have been setting the event class ID to whatever the component/process name was. It just wasn't. After some Googling, I found out the code to build the event class key was just plain broken. After making these &lt;a href="http://lists.zenoss.org/pipermail/zenoss-dev/2008/001892.html"&gt;suggested changes&lt;/a&gt;, I could start mapping events.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Another syslog problem was in parsing the hostname. I have a satellite syslog-ng server in a remote location that logs to my central syslog-ng server. Because of this, the hostname has the relay information in it. Zenoss' syslog support has an option to parse this though, so no problem, right? Despite turning this on, I was still getting entires like IP/IP, so back into the syslog code. It turns out, Zenoss expects the separator between the two hostnames to be "@", and syslog-ng uses "/'. Easy fix in the code, but I suspect this may work for the standard syslog, and it needs to be a configuration option.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Despite all of this, I like Zenoss a lot. I am running it parallel with Nagios until I get all the event handling nailed down. I might need 2 GB RAM on the monitoring server though, and I have already moved the MySQL database onto a different server.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://mysql-python.blogspot.com/2008/05/zenoss-deathmatch.html' title='Zenoss Deathmatch'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=1844829803862335252&amp;postID=6076924685321497970' title='5 Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://mysql-python.blogspot.com/feeds/6076924685321497970/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://mysql-python.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/6076924685321497970'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1844829803862335252/posts/default/6076924685321497970'/><author><name>Andy Dustman</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/13581204403076051529</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-1844829803862335252.post-5552434279562573597</id><published>2008-04-08T17:25:00.004-04:00</published><updated>2008-04-08T17:28:44.808-04:00</updated><category scheme='http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#' term='mysql python'/><title type='text'>CrunchyFrog: A database navigator and query tool for GNOME</title><content type='html'>&lt;div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://cf.andialbrecht.de/"&gt;CrunchyFrog&lt;/a&gt; is a database navigator and query tool for&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.gnome.org/"&gt;GNOME&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Currently PostgreSQL, MySQL, Oracle, SQLite3 databases and LDAP servers are supported for browsing and querying.&lt;p&gt;I gave it quick try and it looks really promising. Gotta love a Monty Python reference in any case.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://mysql-python.blogspot.com/2008/04/crunchyfrog-database-navigator-and.html' title='CrunchyFrog: A database navigator and query tool for GNOME'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=1844829803862335252&amp;postID=5552434279562573597' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://mysql-python.blogspot.com/feeds/5552434279562573597/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://mysql-python.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/5552434279562573597'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1844829803862335252/posts/default/5552434279562573597'/><author><name>Andy Dustman</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/13581204403076051529</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-1844829803862335252.post-716069796255685627</id><published>2008-03-24T16:05:00.002-04:00</published><updated>2008-03-24T16:09:11.723-04:00</updated><category scheme='http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#' term='mysql python django cluster'/><title type='text'>MySQL Cluster support for Django</title><content type='html'>&lt;div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'&gt; Ivan Sagalaev has created a &lt;a href='http://softwaremaniacs.org/soft/mysql_cluster/en/'&gt;mysql_cluster&lt;/a&gt; database backend for &lt;a href='http://www.djangoproject.com/'&gt;Django,&lt;/a&gt; which allows you to configure master and slave servers, and then specify which should be used on given view with &lt;a href='http://www.python.org/'&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href='http://wiki.python.org/moin/PythonDecorators'&gt;decorators&lt;/a&gt;. Found via &lt;a href='http://del.icio.us/tag/mysql+python'&gt;del.icio.us&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href='http://simonwillison.net/2008/Mar/21/mysqlcluster/'&gt;Simon Willison's blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://mysql-python.blogspot.com/2008/03/mysql-cluster-support-for-django.html' title='MySQL Cluster support for Django'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=1844829803862335252&amp;postID=716069796255685627' title='2 Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://mysql-python.blogspot.com/feeds/716069796255685627/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://mysql-python.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/716069796255685627'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1844829803862335252/posts/default/716069796255685627'/><author><name>Andy Dustman</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/13581204403076051529</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-1844829803862335252.post-5295591239065749564</id><published>2008-03-14T16:05:00.002-04:00</published><updated>2008-03-14T16:09:04.938-04:00</updated><category scheme='http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#' term='MySQL'/><category scheme='http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#' term='news'/><category scheme='http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#' term='Python'/><title type='text'>I am not dead</title><content type='html'>&lt;div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'&gt;It's been nearly a year since the last post, so you might naturally wonder if I am dead or stopping development of MySQLdb. Actually I've been sick for the last year and a half or so, and hadn't really been motivated enough to do anything. Here's what's been going on:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href='http://sourceforge.net/users/eikenberry'&gt;John Eikenberry&lt;/a&gt; has taken over development of ZMySQLDA, since I pretty much don't do anything with Zope these days. He's made a couple of releases on the way to a 3.0 release. As far as I know, ZMySQLDA is still only useful with Zope 2 as Zope 3 has a different architecture and comes with MySQL support directly.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Monty Taylor from MySQL AB has volunteered to help out on MySQLdb. I believe the way this is going to work out is he's going to be doing maintenance on the 1.2 branch, and get some minor bug fixes out there. In addition, he has a good start on a native (i.e. written in Python) MySQL driver.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I have a lot of work done towards the first 1.3 version, which will be the development branch (SVN trunk) for 2.0. To a large extent, this is a refactoring project, which means there are a lot of internal changes that don't affect &lt;i&gt;most&lt;/i&gt; users.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;When I first started working on MySQLdb (way back in the last millenium), there was only one option for talking to the MySQL server: Use the C API via libmysqlclient. Then the re-entrant/thread-safe libmysqlclient_r was added. Then the embedded server libmysqld. And now there is the prospect of a native Python version. This makes building more complicated because you currently have to build against one library at a time. It's also more complicated for users: Suppose you want to have both a regular client version and an embedded version on the same system?&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;1.3/2.0 is going to fix this by building all the possible options as separate drivers, and then you can specify which one to use at connect-time, or you can use the default, which will probably go in the order libmysqlclient_r, libmysqlclient, and native. (The embedded version requires special initialization so it should never be a default.)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;1.2 and earlier uses a type conversion dictionary to map MySQL column types to functions which convert a string result to a Python type. Additionally, this same dictionary is used to convert Python types into SQL literals. I think in earlier (pre-1.0) versions, these were separate dictionaries, and they were later combined because they have a disjoint set of keys. I'm not sure now if this was a good idea or not.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;One of the other complications of this approach is TEXT columns. To the MySQL C API, TEXT columns have the same column type as BLOB columns. The difference is the presence of a flag. This took some kludgy stuff to get to work.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Then unicode came along, not just in Python but in MySQL. (The original target versions where MySQL-3.23 and Python-1.5.) This complicated the type conversion because now it was dependent on the connection's character set, which could be changed, so the converter dictionary had to be tinkered with on the fly. Additionally, there were reference count problems (and maybe still are to an extent) with this approach, due in part to the dictionary being about to be overridden by the user.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I haven't decided entirely how this is going to be fixed, but I will have some method for users to override the type conversion at runtime. I will probably have some hooks that will allow you to use a specific conversion for column based on column type, column name, table name, database name, or any combination thereof. For example, you could have a rule that said that any column name ending with "_ip" with a column type of UNSIGNED INTEGER could be returned as a user-defined IP object, but stored in the database as a four-byte integer.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The type conversion from MySQL to Python currently takes place in the low level driver (_mysql). Since there are going to be multiple drivers, this is going to move up into the Python layer. I don't believe this will adversely affect performance. Looking up the right converter is only a dictionary lookup anyway, and only has to be done once per column per query. Once you have a list/tuple of converters for the result set, these can be applied quickly with a list/generator comprehension.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;MySQLdb-1.2 and earlier have several cursor classes which are built with mixin classes. The mixins control things like whether the rows are returned as tuples or dictionaries, or whether a buffered or unbuffered result set is used (i.e. mysql_store_result() vs. mysql_use_result()). This is is pretty messy and is going away.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The format of the row will probably be controlled by a hook of some sort. I'm inclined to using unbuffered cursors, i.e. SSCursor or mysql_use_result(), by default. The tricky part is the entire result set must be fetched before another query can be issued, so if there are multiple cursors, there needs to be a mechanism so that only one can use the connection at a time. Rather than locking the connection, there will need to be a way for one cursor to tell the others that they need to buffer the rest of the result set.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Some of this is already done for the trunk, but needs to be committed. In particular, there is no type conversion at all, and the driver selection is not done yet, but I'll see if I have time to work on it more this week at &lt;a href='http://us.pycon.org/2008/about/'&gt;PyCon 2008&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://mysql-python.blogspot.com/2008/03/i-am-not-dead.html' title='I am not dead'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=1844829803862335252&amp;postID=5295591239065749564' title='2 Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://mysql-python.blogspot.com/feeds/5295591239065749564/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://mysql-python.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/5295591239065749564'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1844829803862335252/posts/default/5295591239065749564'/><author><name>Andy Dustman</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/13581204403076051529</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-1844829803862335252.post-5126503188747866343</id><published>2007-04-30T14:26:00.001-04:00</published><updated>2007-04-30T17:42:49.970-04:00</updated><category scheme='http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#' term='MySQL'/><category scheme='http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#' term='conference'/><category scheme='http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#' term='storage engine'/><category scheme='http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#' term='Python'/><title type='text'>MySQL Conference 2007</title><content type='html'>&lt;div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'&gt;The 2007 MySQL Conference is over, and I finally made it back home. I have some notes on some of the sessions, which really aren't that great, so if you want to see what you missed, you should read &lt;a href='http://www.planetmysql.org/'&gt;Planet MySQL&lt;/a&gt;. But I will give some of the highlights.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;There's a lot of new development around storage engines.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;MySQL-5.1 has a pluggable storage engine architecture which allows you to load and unload storage engines while the server is running. Brian Aker explained that this is for cases where you have a stable server setup and only want to upgrade the storage engine. All the storage engines in 5.1 are pluggable, and there are already some third-party proprietary storage engines available.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;One of the relatively new third-party storage engines is SolidDB. Solid has been around for quite awhile. In fact, I was using Solid for a project in the late 1990's before I started using MySQL.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;a href='http://www-03.ibm.com/press/us/en/pressrelease/21430.wss'&gt;IBM announced a partnership with MySQL AB&lt;/a&gt; to create a DB2 storage engine, but so far this is only on their i5/OS mainframe platform.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;InnoDB is still very much alive and well, despite being purchased a year and a half ago by Oracle. In fact, InnoDB OY has already renewed their OEM agreement with MySQL AB until at least mid-2009, so there is no danger of current InnoDB users being cut off.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Falcon is a new storage engine which will be part of MySQL-6.0 (2008); &lt;a href='http://dev.mysql.com/downloads/mysql/5.2.html'&gt;alpha versions are available now&lt;/a&gt;, and a beta is expected later this year.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.nitrosecurity.com/products/nitroedb-data-management.asp'&gt;NitroEDB&lt;/a&gt; is a storage engine designed to handle heavy insert loads, and for fast aggregate queries. Aggregate values are stored in the index, so many aggregate functions can be evaluated just by looking at a couple of index values.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;a href='http://scaledb.com/'&gt;ScaleDB&lt;/a&gt; uses a &lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Patricia_trie'&gt;Patricia trie index&lt;/a&gt; which is highly compressed compared to a B-tree. The implementation has three relatively small in-memory index layers on top of the trie which minimized disk access.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;MySQL-5.1 adds &lt;a href='http://dev.mysql.com/doc/refman/5.1/en/log-tables.html'&gt;log tables&lt;/a&gt;: The general and slow query logs can be set (on the fly) to record into tables instead of flag log files. The only supported engines for log tables are MyISAM and &lt;a href='http://dev.mysql.com/doc/refman/5.1/en/csv-storage-engine.html'&gt;CSV&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Coolest presentation: Maybe &lt;a href='http://www.mysqlconf.com/cs/mysqluc2007/view/e_sess/10931'&gt;The Declarative Power of Views&lt;/a&gt;. Basically, this is using SQL like &lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Prolog'&gt;Prolog&lt;/a&gt;, and creating an expert system with a couple of views.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Monty Taylor of MySQL AB has wrapped the NDB cluster API with Swig and come up with some APIs for various languages, including Python, and then created a patch for SQLAlchemy so that it could bypass using any SQL for object storage.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Jess Balint of MySQL AB has written a pure Python MySQL driver that looks pretty functional. I'll have more on this in my next post...&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;I held a BoF session for Python users. Considering how late I scheduled it, and that it was up against the MySQL Quiz Show, I had a pretty good turnout. Several MySQL-python users actually had vendor booths: Google uses MySQL (mostly 4.0) and Python for some of their (undisclosed) back-end processes. YouTube (now owned by Google) uses MySQL and Python for some of their user profile stuff. &lt;a href='http://www.snaplogic.com/'&gt;SnapLogic&lt;/a&gt; has a new data integration project written in Python which is using MySQLdb, and presumably other database backends. I seem to remember the &lt;a href='http://www.nitrosecurity.com/'&gt;NitroSecurity&lt;/a&gt; people were using it as well.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;All-in-all, it was a great conference, and O'Reilly kept us all well-fed. Next conference starts April 15, 2008. I'll have to try to be a little better organized for that one.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://mysql-python.blogspot.com/2007/04/mysql-conference-2007.html' title='MySQL Conference 2007'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=1844829803862335252&amp;postID=5126503188747866343' title='3 Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://mysql-python.blogspot.com/feeds/5126503188747866343/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://mysql-python.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/5126503188747866343'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1844829803862335252/posts/default/5126503188747866343'/><author><name>Andy Dustman</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/13581204403076051529</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-1844829803862335252.post-499270800137207855</id><published>2007-04-09T17:47:00.000-04:00</published><updated>2007-04-09T17:51:21.780-04:00</updated><category scheme='http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#' term='MySQL'/><category scheme='http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#' term='Python'/><title type='text'>Projects which use MySQLdb</title><content type='html'>I'm putting together a page of &lt;a href="http://mysql-python.sourceforge.net/projects.html"&gt;projects which use MySQLdb&lt;/a&gt;. If your project is not on this list, leave a comment, with a URL and brief description, and I'll check it out.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class="section"&gt; &lt;h4&gt;&lt;a id="frameworks-libraries" name="frameworks-libraries"&gt;Frameworks/Libraries&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;ul class="simple"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference" href="http://dabodev.com/"&gt;Dabo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference" href="http://www.djangoproject.com/"&gt;Django&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference" href="http://www.sqlalchemy.org/"&gt;SQLAlchemy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference" href="http://www.sqlobject.org/"&gt;SQLObject&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference" href="http://www.turbogears.org/"&gt;Turbogears&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference" href="http://www.webwareforpython.org/"&gt;Webware&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference" href="http://www.zope.org/"&gt;Zope&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="section"&gt; &lt;h4&gt;&lt;a id="applications" name="applications"&gt;Applications&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;ul class="simple"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference" href="http://griffith.berlios.de/pages/download.php"&gt;Griffith&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference" href="http://diotavelli.net/rattlesnake.html"&gt;RattleSnake&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference" href="http://trac.edgewall.org/"&gt;Trac&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference" href="http://roundup.sourceforge.net/"&gt;Roundup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference" href="http://biopython.org/"&gt;Biopython&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://mysql-python.blogspot.com/2007/04/projects-which-use-mysqldb.html' title='Projects which use MySQLdb'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=1844829803862335252&amp;postID=499270800137207855' title='4 Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://mysql-python.blogspot.com/feeds/499270800137207855/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://mysql-python.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/499270800137207855'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1844829803862335252/posts/default/499270800137207855'/><author><name>Andy Dustman</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/13581204403076051529</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-1844829803862335252.post-4880222127426852526</id><published>2007-03-30T14:15:00.000-04:00</published><updated>2007-03-30T15:07:11.418-04:00</updated><category scheme='http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#' term='MySQL'/><category scheme='http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#' term='conference'/><title type='text'>MySQL Conference Agenda</title><content type='html'>Here's my tentative agenda for sessions I am interested in at the &lt;a href="http://www.mysqlconf.com/mysqluc2007/"&gt;MySQL Conference&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.mysqlconf.com/pub/w/54/tutorials.html"&gt;Monday&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.mysqlconf.com/cs/mysqluc2007/view/e_sess/12316"&gt;MySQL 5.1 In-depth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.mysqlconf.com/cs/mysqluc2007/view/e_sess/12080"&gt;Real-World MySQL Performance Tuning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.mysqlconf.com/pub/w/54/sessions.html#Tuesday"&gt;Tuesday&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="url" href="http://www.mysqlconf.com/cs/mysqluc2007/view/e_sess/12203"&gt; Using Stored Routines for MySQL Administration &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="url" href="http://www.mysqlconf.com/cs/mysqluc2007/view/e_sess/10966"&gt; MySQL 5.1's Log Tables&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class="vevent"&gt;&lt;span class="summary"&gt;&lt;a class="url" href="http://www.mysqlconf.com/cs/mysqluc2007/view/e_sess/11021"&gt; Implementing a MySQL Client Library&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class="vevent"&gt;&lt;span class="summary"&gt;&lt;a class="url" href="http://www.mysqlconf.com/cs/mysqluc2007/view/e_sess/10317"&gt; Testing the Security of Your Site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class="vevent"&gt;&lt;span class="summary"&gt;&lt;a class="url" href="http://www.mysqlconf.com/cs/mysqluc2007/view/e_sess/10418"&gt; Falcon Concurrency Control &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class="vevent"&gt;&lt;span class="summary"&gt;&lt;a class="url" href="http://www.mysqlconf.com/cs/mysqluc2007/view/e_sess/10907"&gt; Mission Critical Flight Planning Applications at the U.S. Navy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class="vevent"&gt;&lt;span class="summary"&gt;&lt;a class="url" href="http://www.mysqlconf.com/cs/mysqluc2007/view/e_sess/13986"&gt; How to Build a Highly Scalable News Web Site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.mysqlconf.com/pub/w/54/sessions.html#Wednesday"&gt;Wednesday&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="url" href="http://www.mysqlconf.com/cs/mysqluc2007/view/e_sess/13950"&gt; Clash of the Database Egos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="url" href="http://www.mysqlconf.com/cs/mysqluc2007/view/e_sess/13869"&gt; Versioning Your MySQL Schemas with Ruby on Rails' Migrations&lt;/a&gt; (I don't care about Ruby or Rails but the migrations part interests me)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="url" href="http://www.mysqlconf.com/cs/mysqluc2007/view/e_sess/10931"&gt; The Declarative Power of Views&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a class="url" href="http://www.mysqlconf.com/cs/mysqluc2007/view/e_sess/10992"&gt; Using MySQL as Active RDBMS for Surveillance Applications&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="url" href="http://www.mysqlconf.com/cs/mysqluc2007/view/e_sess/10976"&gt; Running a Top 500 Web Site with LAMP Stack and Commodity Hardware&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="url" href="http://www.mysqlconf.com/cs/mysqluc2007/view/e_sess/12492"&gt; MySQL Server Roadmap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="url" href="http://www.mysqlconf.com/cs/mysqluc2007/view/e_sess/10417"&gt; Inside Falcon: MySQL's Newest Storage Engine &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="url" href="http://www.mysqlconf.com/cs/mysqluc2007/view/e_sess/10913"&gt; MySQL Performance Cookbook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="url" href="http://www.mysqlconf.com/cs/mysqluc2007/view/e_sess/10799"&gt; For Ticketmaster, MySQL Replication is the Ticket!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.mysqlconf.com/pub/w/54/sessions.html#Thursday"&gt;Thursday&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="url" href="http://www.mysqlconf.com/cs/mysqluc2007/view/e_sess/13873"&gt; Implement High Availability with DRBD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class="vevent"&gt;&lt;span class="summary"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="url" href="http://www.mysqlconf.com/cs/mysqluc2007/view/e_sess/10984"&gt; The 7 Stages of Scaling Web Applications: Strategies for Architects &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class="vevent"&gt;&lt;span class="summary"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="url" href="http://www.mysqlconf.com/cs/mysqluc2007/view/e_sess/12448"&gt; What Happens After You're Scalable: Capacity Planning for LAMP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class="vevent"&gt;&lt;span class="summary"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="url" href="http://www.mysqlconf.com/cs/mysqluc2007/view/e_sess/12456"&gt; ScaleDB: A Scalable and High Performance Transactional Engine for MySQL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class="vevent"&gt;&lt;span class="summary"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class="url" href="http://www.mysqlconf.com/cs/mysqluc2007/view/e_sess/10671"&gt; ORM on Steroids: Using the NDBAPI Directly in Your Mapping Layer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</content><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://mysql-python.blogspot.com/2007/03/mysql-conference-agenda.html' title='MySQL Conference Agenda'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=1844829803862335252&amp;postID=4880222127426852526' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://mysql-python.blogspot.com/feeds/4880222127426852526/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://mysql-python.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/4880222127426852526'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1844829803862335252/posts/default/4880222127426852526'/><author><name>Andy Dustman</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/13581204403076051529</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-1844829803862335252.post-5015598091751517612</id><published>2007-03-28T21:19:00.000-04:00</published><updated>2007-03-28T21:31:53.532-04:00</updated><category scheme='http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#' term='MySQL'/><category scheme='http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#' term='conference'/><category scheme='http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#' term='Python'/><title type='text'>Some previous MySQL Confererence posts</title><content type='html'>Just for reference, here are some previous posts I did for the 2005 MySQL User Conference:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://farcepest.blogspot.com/2005/04/mysql-uc-day-0.html"&gt;Day 0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://farcepest.blogspot.com/2005/04/mysql-uc-day-1.html"&gt;Day 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://farcepest.blogspot.com/2005/04/mysql-uc-day-2.html"&gt;Day 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://farcepest.blogspot.com/2005/04/mysql-uc-day-3.html"&gt;Day 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://farcepest.blogspot.com/2005/04/mysql-uc-day-4.html"&gt;Day 4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;Not that these are particularly awesome or anything, but there are a few travels notes which may possibly be useful if you decide to go this year, since it's in the same location.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you have the time, and you are from outside The Valley, catch &lt;a href="http://www.caltrain.com/"&gt;CalTrain&lt;/a&gt; and head out to San Francisco.</content><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://mysql-python.blogspot.com/2007/03/some-previous-mysql-confererence-posts.html' title='Some previous MySQL Confererence posts'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=1844829803862335252&amp;postID=5015598091751517612' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://mysql-python.blogspot.com/feeds/5015598091751517612/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://mysql-python.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/5015598091751517612'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1844829803862335252/posts/default/5015598091751517612'/><author><name>Andy Dustman</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/13581204403076051529</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-1844829803862335252.post-3379463855492807635</id><published>2007-03-27T22:29:00.000-04:00</published><updated>2007-03-27T22:40:44.545-04:00</updated><category scheme='http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#' term='MySQL'/><category scheme='http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#' term='conference'/><category scheme='http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#' term='swag'/><category scheme='http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#' term='Python'/><title type='text'>MySQL Conference &amp; Expo 2007</title><content type='html'>Thanks to a gift from &lt;a href="http://www.mysql.com/"&gt;MySQL AB&lt;/a&gt;, I'll be attending the &lt;a href="http://www.mysqlconf.com/"&gt;MySQL Conference &amp; Expo 2007&lt;/a&gt;. I &lt;a href="http://www.mysqlconf.com/cs/mysqluc2005/view/e_sess/6289"&gt;presented&lt;/a&gt; at the 2005 conference, and found the conference itself to be pretty educational. Plus the food is generally pretty good at the O'Reilly conferences. Of course the real reason people to conferences is for the swag. Now this year's &lt;a href="http://pycon.blogspot.com/"&gt;PyCon&lt;/a&gt; had some pretty good swag; I got at least six free T-shirts and two Rubik's cubes. So top that.</content><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://mysql-python.blogspot.com/2007/03/mysql-conference-expo-2007.html' title='MySQL Conference &amp; Expo 2007'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=1844829803862335252&amp;postID=3379463855492807635' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://mysql-python.blogspot.com/feeds/3379463855492807635/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://mysql-python.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/3379463855492807635'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1844829803862335252/posts/default/3379463855492807635'/><author><name>Andy Dustman</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/13581204403076051529</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email></author></entry></feed>