<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title type="text">about:cmlenz (Christopher Lenz) on python</title>
  <link rel="self" href="http://www.cmlenz.net/archives/python/feed.xml"/>
  <link rel="alternate" href="/archives/python/" type="text/html"/>
  <link rel="next" href="/archives/python/?p=2" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <link rel="last" href="/archives/python/?p=14" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <icon>/media/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>/media/style/logo.png</logo>
  <updated>2008-04-15T17:52:09Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Christopher Lenz</name>
    <email>cmlenz@gmx.de</email>
  </author>
  <id>http://www.cmlenz.net/archives/python/</id>
  <entry>
  <title>Offline</title>
  <category term="genshi" scheme="http://www.cmlenz.net/publish/categories/"/><category term="google" scheme="http://www.cmlenz.net/publish/categories/"/><category term="personal" scheme="http://www.cmlenz.net/publish/categories/"/><category term="python" scheme="http://www.cmlenz.net/publish/categories/"/>
  <link rel="alternate" href="/archives/2008/04/offline" type="text/html"/>
  <id>tag:www.cmlenz.net,2008-04-15:A7EFD0BBDD9152947D11DD80CD385580</id>
  <published>2008-04-15T17:52:09Z</published>
  <updated>2008-04-15T17:52:09Z</updated>
  <summary>On vacation for the next three weeks.</summary>
  <content type="xhtml">
    <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xml:space="preserve">
      <div>
      <p>I'm going on vacation for three weeks starting in a couple hours, and I'll have little to no access to the net. So I'll be even less responsive to email and all that than I am anyway.</p>
      <p>I would've really liked to make a <a href="http://genshi.edgewall.org/">Genshi</a> 0.5 release before leaving, but unfortunately that didn't work out. Just as we were closing in on the last couple of tickets, Google came out with <a href="http://code.google.com/appengine/">App Engine</a>, which Genshi currently does not work with due to various restrictions in the hosting environment. And I'd really like the 0.5 release to be usable with App Engine (some <a href="http://genshi.edgewall.org/wiki/AppEngine">progress</a> has been made on a <a href="http://genshi.edgewall.org/browser/branches/experimental/appengine">branch</a>), so the release will have to wait until I'm back.</p>
    </div>
      
    </div>
  </content>
</entry><entry>
  <title>Python httplib Performance Problems</title>
  <category term="couchdb" scheme="http://www.cmlenz.net/publish/categories/"/><category term="python" scheme="http://www.cmlenz.net/publish/categories/"/><category term="web development" scheme="http://www.cmlenz.net/publish/categories/"/>
  <link rel="alternate" href="/archives/2008/03/python-httplib-performance-problems" type="text/html"/>
  <id>tag:www.cmlenz.net,2008-03-25:12A6C7B35526010D20CC4FD2224024B0</id>
  <published>2008-03-25T13:50:04Z</published>
  <updated>2008-03-26T11:38:21Z</updated>
  <summary>Having trouble figuring out an awkward performance issue with Python httplib on Linux.</summary>
  <content type="xhtml">
    <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xml:space="preserve">
      <p>I've run into a tricky performance problem with my <a href="http://code.google.com/p/couchdb-python/">CouchDB client for Python</a>.</p>
<p>I recently started getting some <a href="http://dev.jmoiron.net/couchtest.html">reports</a> about really bad performance of the client on Linux, where you apparently couldn't get more than about 25 requests per second in throughput (that number may <a href="http://www.jacobian.org/writing/2007/oct/18/couchdb/">sound familiar</a>.) I develop on Mac OS X, and could not reproduce the problem. In fact, on OS X <code>couchdb-python</code> was often faster than the other methods. But when I went on to run the performance tests on this server (a Debian 4 install with Python 2.4.4, running on a Xen-powered Linode), I was seeing the very same problem.</p>
<p>So I've been trying to figure out where the code is going wrong. And right now I'm just puzzled. I'd be grateful if anyone could point me in the right direction.</p>
      <p>
        <a href="/archives/2008/03/python-httplib-performance-problems#more">read on …</a>
      </p>
    </div>
  </content>
</entry><entry>
  <title>Genshi Slot @ GSoC 2008</title>
  <category term="genshi" scheme="http://www.cmlenz.net/publish/categories/"/><category term="google" scheme="http://www.cmlenz.net/publish/categories/"/><category term="python" scheme="http://www.cmlenz.net/publish/categories/"/><category term="turbogears" scheme="http://www.cmlenz.net/publish/categories/"/><category term="web development" scheme="http://www.cmlenz.net/publish/categories/"/>
  <link rel="alternate" href="/archives/2008/03/genshi-slot-gsoc-2008" type="text/html"/>
  <id>tag:www.cmlenz.net,2008-03-20:EF379DEA036191F961A91FB5776F3588</id>
  <published>2008-03-20T12:07:30Z</published>
  <updated>2008-03-20T12:07:30Z</updated>
  <summary>Come work on improving performance of Genshi as your Google Summer of Code project.</summary>
  <content type="xhtml">
    <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xml:space="preserve">
      <div>
      <p>The <a href="http://turbogears.org/">TurboGears</a> project has been <a href="http://www.blueskyonmars.com/2008/03/20/turbogears-looking-for-google-soc-students/">accepted as a mentoring organization</a> for the <a href="http://code.google.com/soc/2008/">Google Summer of Code</a> program this year. The <a href="http://docs.turbogears.org/GSoC/Ideas2008#genshi-compatibility-and-performance">project ideas</a> include two around <a href="http://genshi.edgewall.org/">Genshi</a>: generally improved performance, and compatibility with <a href="http://www.jython.org/">Jython</a>. Both tricky. I volunteered to act as mentor for the performance improvements project.</p>
      <p>If you're a student with solid knowledge of both Python and XML/HTML, and you're looking for a GSoC project that's both interesting and challenging, start by reading <a href="http://groups.google.com/group/genshi/msg/19d3aa25f91c6cf7">my own ideas</a> for performance work. The Genshi code makes intensive use of Python language features such as closures and generators, and then there's also AST transformation and bytecode generation going on. The thing is that much of the low-hanging fruit for optimization has already been picked. In trunk we even have a <code>_speedups</code> extension written in C. So making major advancements in performance will require some thinking outside the box.</p>
      <p>If you have any questions, ask on the the Genshi <a href="http://genshi.edgewall.org/wiki/MailingList">mailing list</a>, and/or come visit us on our <a href="http://genshi.edgewall.org/wiki/IrcChannel">IRC channel</a>. See also the <a href="http://groups.google.com/group/turbogears/msg/6c9f08aea82c0534">announcement</a> on the TurboGears <a href="http://groups.google.com/group/turbogears">mailing list</a> and the <a href="http://code.google.com/opensource/gsoc/2008/faqs.html">GSoC FAQs</a> for more information.</p>
    </div>
      
    </div>
  </content>
</entry><entry>
  <title>Eating My Own Dogfood</title>
  <category term="babel" scheme="http://www.cmlenz.net/publish/categories/"/><category term="couchdb" scheme="http://www.cmlenz.net/publish/categories/"/><category term="genshi" scheme="http://www.cmlenz.net/publish/categories/"/><category term="python" scheme="http://www.cmlenz.net/publish/categories/"/><category term="web development" scheme="http://www.cmlenz.net/publish/categories/"/>
  <link rel="alternate" href="/archives/2008/01/eating-my-own-dogfood" type="text/html"/>
  <id>tag:www.cmlenz.net,2008-01-18:15C520CE0F2210DFA1A157A7AB198B63</id>
  <published>2008-01-18T18:46:42Z</published>
  <updated>2008-01-18T18:46:42Z</updated>
  <summary>After a couple of years of hosting on TypePad, I've finally managed to move this site onto my own server (a Linode virtual host), running on top of my currently favored set of tools.</summary>
  <content type="xhtml">
    <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xml:space="preserve">
      <p>After a couple of years of hosting on <a href="http://typepad.com/">TypePad</a>, I've finally managed to move this site onto my own server (a <a href="http://www.linode.com/">Linode</a> virtual host), running on top of my currently favored set of tools.</p>
    <p>The blog software has been written from scratch. It uses <a href="http://couchdb.org/">CouchDB</a> (via the <a href="http://code.google.com/p/couchdb-python/">CouchDB Python library</a>) for storage, <a href="http://genshi.edgewall.org/">Genshi</a> for templating, and <a href="http://babel.edgewall.org/">Babel</a> for, well, basically just date/time formatting. It's based on a custom <a href="http://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0333/">WSGI</a>-enabled Python web framework that I've been hacking on from time to time, basically as a playground for me to test various ideas. You can get a very basic impression of that framework <a href="http://scratchpad.cmlenz.net/28BC09BF15CB7E70D8B1DA9470794FD4/">here</a>. Look Mom, No Classes! Oh, and that <a href="http://scratchpad.cmlenz.net/">scratchpad site</a> I just linked to is based on the same stack as this blog (plus <a href="http://pygments.org/">Pygments</a> for the fancy colors.) The code isn't publicly available at this point, although I do intend to release it when I feel it's ready. Just in case anyone needs another Python web framework to choose from.</p>
    <p>The trackback functionality provided by TypePad has been removed, but I'll look into adding solid support for comments and pingback/trackback soon-ish.</p>
      
    </div>
  </content>
</entry><entry>
  <title>Python on Leopard</title>
  <category term="apple" scheme="http://www.cmlenz.net/publish/categories/"/><category term="python" scheme="http://www.cmlenz.net/publish/categories/"/><category term="trac" scheme="http://www.cmlenz.net/publish/categories/"/>
  <link rel="alternate" href="/archives/2007/10/python-on-leopard" type="text/html"/>
  <id>tag:www.cmlenz.net,2007-10-31:BAFBEC81F32E40A12E40A58F63916627</id>
  <published>2007-10-31T00:33:57Z</published>
  <updated>2007-11-06T19:25:19Z</updated>
  <summary>As I haven't seen anyone writing much about the state of Python development on Mac OS X Leopard, here's a quick rundown. Leopard comes with Python 2.5.1 installed (OS X previously came with Python 2.3). And the interactive interpreter is now quite usable out of the box, as it includes the readline stuff you previously had to install by hand.</summary>
  <content type="xhtml">
    <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xml:space="preserve">
      <p>As I haven't seen anyone writing much about the state of Python development on Mac OS X Leopard, here's a quick rundown. Leopard comes with Python 2.5.1 installed (OS X previously came with Python 2.3). And the interactive interpreter is now quite usable out of the box, as it includes the <code>readline</code> stuff you previously had to <a href="http://www.macosxhints.com/article.php?story=20050107140338573">install by hand</a>.</p>

<p>The <a href="http://peak.telecommunity.com/DevCenter/setuptools">setuptools/eggs</a> infrastructure is also available by default, meaning that tons of third-party packages are just an <code>easy_install</code> incantation away. Quite a number of other packages come preinstalled (at least with the developer tools), such as <a href="http://numpy.scipy.org/">numpy</a>, <a href="http://www.wxpython.org/">wxPython</a>, <code>zope.interface</code> and at least some parts of <a href="http://twistedmatrix.com/trac/">Twisted</a>.</p>

<p>And then there's the whole <a href="http://www.friday.com/bbum/2007/10/27/pyobjc-20-pyobjc-in-leopard/">PyObjC and BridgeSupport story</a>, which should be great news for anyone interested in doing Mac OS X development with Python. Personally, I know nothing about this stuff, but being able to <code>import WebKit</code> gives me warm fuzzies (yeah, I'm weird).</p>

<p>For (potential) <a href="http://trac.edgewall.org/">Trac</a> users and developers, you should be delighted to learn that Leopard comes with SQLite 3.4, Subversion 1.4.4, and Apache HTTPD 2.2.6 (including <code>mod_dav_svn</code>) installed. The Python bindings for SQLite are part of Python 2.5, so there's nothing you need to do to use SQLite from Python. But also, Leopard includes the Python bindings for Subversion, so there's nothing needed in that area either.</p>

<p>When Trac 0.11 finally gets released (another story for another post), it'll be a simple matter of:</p>

<pre>
  easy_install Trac
</pre>

<p>to get Trac up and running, including the default SQLite database backend and Subversion integration. That command will automatically download and install <a href="http://genshi.edgewall.org/">Genshi</a> for templating. About as easy as it gets. On the flip side, neither <code>mod_wsgi</code> nor <code>mod_python</code> are installed by default, but hey, you got to draw the line somewhere, I guess.</p>

<p>There's tons of other really nice things for developers, of course. A much better <code>Terminal.app</code>, <a href="http://www.apple.com/macosx/developertools/instruments.html">Instruments</a>, and updated versions of many (if not all) of those tools we depend upon every day, such as <code>make</code> and <code>autoconf</code>. Ruby got <a href="http://ruby.macosforge.org/">similar love</a> as Python. Java, <a href="http://www.javalobby.org/java/forums/t102936.html">not so much</a>, at least <a href="http://stuffthathappens.com/blog/2007/10/28/os-x-java-definitive-timeline/">for now</a>.</p>

      
    </div>
  </content>
</entry><entry>
  <title>CouchDB "Joins"</title>
  <category term="couchdb" scheme="http://www.cmlenz.net/publish/categories/"/><category term="python" scheme="http://www.cmlenz.net/publish/categories/"/><category term="web development" scheme="http://www.cmlenz.net/publish/categories/"/>
  <link rel="alternate" href="/archives/2007/10/couchdb-joins" type="text/html"/>
  <id>tag:www.cmlenz.net,2007-10-25:B8057DADBCDB7E06BBF54EE6B0148581</id>
  <published>2007-10-25T00:34:15Z</published>
  <updated>2007-10-31T10:06:54Z</updated>
  <summary>I've been playing more and more with CouchDB lately. After putting together a Python library, I worked on a brand new included HTML/AJAX interface. Now I'm starting to dive into the Erlang code, which is my first serious encounter with Erlang. In particular, I started a branch that aims to replace the HTTP server underpinnings with Bob Ippolito´s not-quite-released-yet Mochiweb library.</summary>
  <content type="xhtml">
    <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xml:space="preserve">
      <a href="http://incubator.apache.org/incubator" title="CouchDB"><img class="figure right" src="http://svn.apache.org/repos/asf/incubator/couchdb/trunk/share/www/image/logo.png" alt="CouchDB - relax" width="175" height="150"/></a>

<p>I've been playing more and more with <a href="http://couchdb.org/">CouchDB</a> lately. After putting together a <a href="http://code.google.com/p/couchdb-python/">Python library</a>, I worked on a brand new included <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/jacobian/1626785307/">HTML/AJAX interface</a>. Now I'm starting to dive into the Erlang code, which is my first serious encounter with Erlang. In particular, I started a <a href="http://couchdb.googlecode.com/svn/branches/mochiweb/">branch</a> that aims to replace the HTTP server underpinnings with <a href="http://bob.pythonmac.org/">Bob Ippolito</a>´s not-quite-released-yet <a href="http://www.rsaccon.com/2007/09/mochiweb-erlang-based-webserver-toolkit.html">Mochiweb</a> library.</p>

<p>Despite all that activity (and past experience with the conceptually similar Lotus Notes), the correct approach to designing applications “the CouchDB way” isn't always obvious to me at this point. Just today, there was a discussion on IRC how you'd go about modeling a simple blogging system with “post” and “comment” entities, where any blog post might have N comments. If you'd be using an SQL database, you'd obviously have two tables with foreign keys and you'd be using joins. (At least until you needed to add some <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Denormalization">denormalization</a>.)</p>

<p>But what would the “obvious” approach in CouchDB look like?</p>

<p style="margin: 1em 2em"><em><strong>Note:</strong> I've updated this post to clarify the role of view collation, and to stress that all three approaches are equally valid for different kinds of applications.</em></p>
      <p>
        <a href="/archives/2007/10/couchdb-joins#more">read on …</a>
      </p>
    </div>
  </content>
</entry><entry>
  <title>CouchDB via Python</title>
  <category term="couchdb" scheme="http://www.cmlenz.net/publish/categories/"/><category term="python" scheme="http://www.cmlenz.net/publish/categories/"/><category term="web development" scheme="http://www.cmlenz.net/publish/categories/"/>
  <link rel="alternate" href="/archives/2007/09/couchdb-via-python" type="text/html"/>
  <id>tag:www.cmlenz.net,2007-09-27:BCF2901C58FCA2AE30F6AE0C206312AC</id>
  <published>2007-09-27T21:42:55Z</published>
  <updated>2007-10-25T19:14:02Z</updated>
  <summary>I've been playing with CouchDB lately, which looks like an interesting approach to data storage in many kinds of web applications. It's basically the backend part of Lotus Notes, but done right. (I'm actually old enough to have done my share of Notes development, and it sucked badly. I still think CouchDB is intriguing.)</summary>
  <content type="xhtml">
    <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xml:space="preserve">
      <p>I've been playing with <a href="http://couchdb.com/">CouchDB</a> lately, which looks like an interesting approach to data storage in many kinds of web applications. It's basically the backend part of Lotus Notes, but done right. (I'm actually old enough to have done my share of Notes development, and it <a href="http://homepage.mac.com/bradster/iarchitect/lotus.htm">sucked badly</a>. I <em>still</em> think CouchDB is intriguing.)</p>

<p>So, I ended up writing a Python library for interfacing with CouchDB. That's actually a fairly simple task, as CouchDB uses a RESTful HTTP interface, and JSON for data encoding.</p>

<p>You can get the library from <a href="http://pypi.python.org/pypi/CouchDB">PyPI</a> (the actual project is on <a href="http://code.google.com/p/couchdb-python/">Google Code</a>), but please be aware that it only works with the current development version of CouchDB: the 0.6.4 release and any previous releases will not work. And of course the library is in alpha stage, as is CouchDB itself. Still, it's pretty interesting, and I encourage everyone to <a href="http://www.couchdbwiki.com/">check it out</a>.</p>
      
    </div>
  </content>
</entry><entry>
  <title>Django/Babel Integration</title>
  <category term="babel" scheme="http://www.cmlenz.net/publish/categories/"/><category term="django" scheme="http://www.cmlenz.net/publish/categories/"/><category term="python" scheme="http://www.cmlenz.net/publish/categories/"/><category term="web development" scheme="http://www.cmlenz.net/publish/categories/"/>
  <link rel="alternate" href="/archives/2007/09/djangobabel-integration" type="text/html"/>
  <id>tag:www.cmlenz.net,2007-09-12:3BA3AE5A5E30CCC7866C24D392204A3E</id>
  <published>2007-09-12T00:02:39Z</published>
  <updated>2007-09-27T19:47:13Z</updated>
  <summary>This might have gone lost, either due to lack of interest, or due to myself having been flagged by some magical and over-ambitious “troll” filter on the django-developers mailing list. Anyway…</summary>
  <content type="xhtml">
    <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xml:space="preserve">
      <p>This might have gone lost, either due to lack of interest, or due to myself having been flagged by some magical and over-ambitious “troll” filter on the <a href="http://groups.google.com/group/django-developers">django-developers mailing list</a>. Anyway…</p>

<p>I recently released a <a href="http://babel.edgewall.org/wiki/BabelDjango">project</a> that provides integration between <a href="http://www.djangoproject.com/">Django</a> and <a href="http://babel.edgewall.org/">Babel</a>. This improves the support for internationalization and localization in Django quite a bit, in my humble opinion. The project is based on work by Ramiro Morales and Massimo Scamarcia, so kudos to them.</p>

      <p>
        <a href="/archives/2007/09/djangobabel-integration#more">read on …</a>
      </p>
    </div>
  </content>
</entry><entry>
  <title>Genshi Tutorial</title>
  <category term="genshi" scheme="http://www.cmlenz.net/publish/categories/"/><category term="python" scheme="http://www.cmlenz.net/publish/categories/"/><category term="web development" scheme="http://www.cmlenz.net/publish/categories/"/>
  <link rel="alternate" href="/archives/2007/09/genshi-tutorial" type="text/html"/>
  <id>tag:www.cmlenz.net,2007-09-05:8DB30077C022E26084BA9620ED88C946</id>
  <published>2007-09-05T17:32:48Z</published>
  <updated>2007-09-27T19:45:21Z</updated>
  <summary>Genshi has pretty good reference documentation (if I may say so myself), but what was missing was something that would walk you through creating an application that uses Genshi, pointing out best practices and the like. All of the examples that came with Genshi were very basic, and the only other option for learning the library was to study the code of an application that uses it, such as Trac or Posterity. But in general, real-world applications are just too complex to be helpful in this respect.</summary>
  <content type="xhtml">
    <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xml:space="preserve">
      <p><a href="http://genshi.edgewall.org/">Genshi</a> has pretty good reference documentation (if I may say so myself), but what was missing was something that would walk you through creating an application that uses Genshi, pointing out best practices and the like. All of the examples that came with Genshi were very basic, and the only other option for learning the library was to study the code of an application that uses it, such as <a href="http://trac.edgewall.org/">Trac</a> or <a href="http://posterity.edgewall.org/">Posterity</a>. But in general, real-world applications are just too complex to be helpful in this respect.</p>

<p>So last week, after <a href="http://michael.susens-schurter.com/">Michael Schurter</a> pointed out this glaring hole in Genshi's plans for world dominance, I started putting together a <a href="http://genshi.edgewall.org/wiki/GenshiTutorial">tutorial</a> on how you'd use Genshi in a web-app. And today the finishing touches have been put on it.</p>

<p>The <a href="http://genshi.edgewall.org/wiki/GenshiTutorial">tutorial</a> guides you through the process of building a (very) stripped down version of <a href="http://reddit.com/">reddit.com</a>, dubbed “<strong>geddit?</strong>”. It uses <a href="http://cherrypy.org/">CherryPy</a> for the HTTP, <a href="http://formencode.org/">FormEncode</a> for the validation, and, well, Genshi for the output. To keep things simple, there's no ORM or SQL; instead persistence is implemented using <code>pickle</code>, i.e. native Python serialization.</p>

<p>I believe the tutorial has turned out pretty nicely. Using a simple application, it conveys a good number of usage patterns and best practices, and not necessarily limited to Genshi: it should also be a good read for anyone interested in CherryPy, and even Python and/or web development in general.</p>

      
    </div>
  </content>
</entry><entry>
  <title>Bitten Redux</title>
  <category term="bitten" scheme="http://www.cmlenz.net/publish/categories/"/><category term="python" scheme="http://www.cmlenz.net/publish/categories/"/><category term="trac" scheme="http://www.cmlenz.net/publish/categories/"/>
  <link rel="alternate" href="/archives/2007/08/bitten-redux" type="text/html"/>
  <id>tag:www.cmlenz.net,2007-08-05:D402FF190865398DCB27D8A90A5CB781</id>
  <published>2007-08-05T19:29:37Z</published>
  <updated>2007-09-27T19:45:22Z</updated>
  <summary>After my recent post on the status of the Bitten project, a couple of folks spoke up on the mailing list to  say that they're using Bitten with some success, or at least would like to, which really encouraged me to start working on the project again. Sometimes these “small things” can make a real difference.</summary>
  <content type="xhtml">
    <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xml:space="preserve">
      <p>After my recent <a href="http://www.cmlenz.net/archives/2007/06/bitten-status-update">post</a> on the status of the <a href="http//bitten.edgewall.org/">Bitten project</a>, a couple of folks spoke up on the mailing list to  say that they're using Bitten with some success, or at least would like to, which really encouraged me to start working on the project again. Sometimes these “small things” can make a real difference.</p>

<p>So I'm happy to say that Bitten is back, it is moving over to <a href="http://bitten.edgewall.org/">edgewall.org</a>, and has already seen some <a href="http://bitten.edgewall.org/wiki/MasterSlaveProtocolHttp">big sweeping changes</a> to get rid of some serious flaws in the initial design. I'm hoping that given another couple of weeks, there'll be a new release that'll truly rock.</p>
      <p>
        <a href="/archives/2007/08/bitten-redux#more">read on …</a>
      </p>
    </div>
  </content>
</entry>
</feed>