<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.blogger.com/styles/atom.css" type="text/css"?><feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom' xmlns:openSearch='http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/'><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-1772927538588141564</id><updated>2008-05-14T13:09:52.071-07:00</updated><title type='text'>__boss__</title><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://dunderboss.blogspot.com/search/label/python'/><link rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://dunderboss.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://dunderboss.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/-/python'/><author><name>Philip Jenvey</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/17437958274873977298</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email></author><generator version='7.00' uri='http://www.blogger.com'>Blogger</generator><openSearch:totalResults>3</openSearch:totalResults><openSearch:startIndex>1</openSearch:startIndex><openSearch:itemsPerPage>25</openSearch:itemsPerPage><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-1772927538588141564.post-3920833324528504343</id><published>2008-05-13T21:40:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2008-05-13T23:00:10.907-07:00</updated><category scheme='http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#' term='jython'/><category scheme='http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#' term='python'/><title type='text'>Jython @ JavaOne 2008</title><content type='html'>I attended a couple days of JavaOne last week and luckily avoided the norovirus outbreak. However I did notice something else spreading through Moscone Center; interest in languages on the JVM. For example:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; The number of sessions/BoFs covering Dynamic Language topics: around 8 on Groovy, 5 on JRuby, 2 on Jython and also a couple on Scala and Rhino each, with some very good turnouts. That's not even including CommunityOne. Also featured was a Scripting language bowl: a faceoff between JRuby, Groovy, Scala and Jython.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; The JavaOne book store was stocked with just about every JRuby and Groovy book out there. Of the top 10 selling books at JavaOne, &lt;a href="http://www.adam-bien.com/roller/abien/entry/the_top_selling_books_at"&gt;3 were about languages on top of the JVM &lt;/a&gt; (Groovy and JavaFX). &lt;a href="http://www.adam-bien.com/roller/abien/entry/wednesday_s_top_selling_books"&gt;Wednesday's top 10 sellers&lt;/a&gt; also included JRuby committer Ola Bini's Practical JRuby on Rails as well as another Rails book. I'm hoping to see a whole lot of Python books on the shelf next year. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;A number of Ruby/JRuby folks (and not just the ones employed by Sun either) told me that they are quite happy with NetBeans' support for Ruby. It has code completion and even some refactoring support. Tor Norbye and the NetBeans crew are now working on JavaScript support (&lt;a href="http://blogs.sun.com/tor/entry/javascript_type_inference"&gt;Look Mom, JavaScript type inference&lt;/a&gt;) and are slated to add Python support next. Ted Leung has already begun talking to them about the details.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.eweek.com/c/a/Application-Development/Ruby-is-on-the-Rise/"&gt;Ruby is still on the rise&lt;/a&gt;, and JRuby is a big contributing factor. JRuby definitely had the attention of many attendees and definitely has a growing userbase in Java land.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; Groovy and the Groovy on Grails combo is also on the rise. linkedin.com, Sky TV and SAP's Composition on Grails Product are a few notable users of Grails. IBM's Project Zero (aka the WebSphere sMash product) is also utilizing Groovy, as well as their own PHP on the JVM implementation.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; As for a language he'd use *now* on top of the JVM, except Java, &lt;a href="http://www.adam-bien.com/roller/abien/entry/java_net_javaone_which_programming"&gt;James Gosling endorses Scala&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sun's own new scripting lanuguage on top of the JVM, JavaFX, was of course all over the place.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; John Rose: "&lt;span style="font-style: italic;"&gt;I think we are on the right track here, letting the JVM grow independently of the Java language. (The language, if it has room to grow, will catch up.) James Gosling expressed a similar sentiment at his February Java Users Group talk “The Feel of Java, Revisited”, when he said he sometimes felt more interested in the future of the JVM than that of the Java language. “I don’t really care about the Java language. All the magic is in the JVM specification.” (Yes, I think that is hyperbolic. No, he is not abandoning Java.) I love both Java and the JVM, and I am pushing on the JVM this year.&lt;/span&gt;"&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; The potential  Java 7 new features. They're still potential because the Java 7 JSR isn't out yet. While some are nice (like &lt;a href="http://blogs.sun.com/jrose/entry/the_golden_spike"&gt;John Rose's JSR 292&lt;/a&gt;, which will be a big help for JVM languages like Jython), some are arguably not nice. I hear more disdain than ever over where Java the language is going, which makes other languages on top of the JVM even more desirable.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; I met many new people (more than I expected) who have used Jython at some point in their career, and some who are using it now (like &lt;a href="http://www.theserverside.com/news/thread.tss?thread_id=49332"&gt;pushToTest's Frank Cohen&lt;/a&gt;). They're all eager about its recent progress and can't wait for the 2.5 release.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Reminder: the Java world is large. Over 10,000 attendees, probably 10 times as many as this year's PyCon. All potential Python converts, right?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;Ok, I mostly covered what I observed about different JVM languages at JavaOne, not just Jython. What I'm getting at here is that there's a lot of potential for the Jython 2.5 release (and all that code waiting around on &lt;a href="http://pypi.python.org/pypi"&gt;Pypi&lt;/a&gt; to run on it) in this large Java ecosystem.</content><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://dunderboss.blogspot.com/2008/05/jython-javaone-2008.html' title='Jython @ JavaOne 2008'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=1772927538588141564&amp;postID=3920833324528504343' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://dunderboss.blogspot.com/feeds/3920833324528504343/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://dunderboss.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/3920833324528504343'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1772927538588141564/posts/default/3920833324528504343'/><author><name>Philip Jenvey</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/17437958274873977298</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-1772927538588141564.post-8040054231671637363</id><published>2008-05-04T17:41:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2008-05-04T21:25:30.578-07:00</updated><category scheme='http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#' term='jython'/><category scheme='http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#' term='python'/><category scheme='http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#' term='pylons'/><title type='text'>You Must Construct Additional Pylons (on other VMs)</title><content type='html'>&lt;a onblur="try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}" href="http://bp1.blogger.com/_aoPwdhKitjA/SB50CHONurI/AAAAAAAAAAM/Fbn-ktrPIEo/s1600-h/Starcraft-Pylon.gif"&gt;&lt;img style="margin: 0pt 0pt 10px 10px; float: right; cursor: pointer; width: 133px; height: 133px;" src="http://bp1.blogger.com/_aoPwdhKitjA/SB50CHONurI/AAAAAAAAAAM/Fbn-ktrPIEo/s200/Starcraft-Pylon.gif" alt="" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5196718599679359666" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Occasionally on the &lt;a href="irc://irc.freenode.net/#pylons"&gt;Pylons IRC Channel&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="http://groups.google.com/group/pylons-discuss"&gt;mailing list&lt;/a&gt; someone will reference the game Starcraft, where "Pylons" are structures that act as a power source. Sometimes the game vocally instructs you to construct additional Pylons.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You could say that last month we've constructed a couple additional Pylons, and by that I mean made Pylons run on different environments:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;o &lt;a href="http://wiki.python.org/jython/PylonsOnJython"&gt;Pylons on Jython trunk!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;o &lt;a href="http://code.google.com/p/appengine-monkey/wiki/Pylons"&gt;Pylons on Google App Engine&lt;/a&gt; via &lt;a href="http://code.google.com/p/appengine-monkey/"&gt;Ian Bicking's appengine-monkey&lt;/a&gt; and mako trunk&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="http://wiki.python.org/jython/PylonsOnJython"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;With the development versions of both Pylons and its dependencies (and the &lt;a href="http://svn.makotemplates.org/mako/branches/jython/"&gt;Mako jython branch&lt;/a&gt;) I'm now able to create the &lt;a href="http://wiki.pylonshq.com/display/pylonsdocs/Flickr+Search+Tutorial"&gt;flicksearch tutorial app from the Pylons Official Docs&lt;/a&gt; on Jython.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The Mako jython branch uses Python 2.5's _ast module, which Jython  now supports thanks to &lt;a href="http://fwierzbicki.blogspot.com/2008/04/start-of-ast-module-in-jythons-trunk.html"&gt;Frank Wierzbicki's recent work&lt;/a&gt;. Mako's also using &lt;a href="http://lucumr.pocoo.org/cogitations/2008/03/30/high-level-ast-module-for-python/"&gt;Armin Ronacher's handy ast module&lt;/a&gt; that'll hopefully &lt;a href="http://mail.python.org/pipermail/python-dev/2008-April/078950.html"&gt;find its way into the stdlib&lt;/a&gt;. Frank and I are still working on smoothing out a couple of our _ast's rough edges, hence the separate Mako jython branch, but Mako is in good shape with 95% of its 214 tests passing (with most of those failures due to the lack of PEP 263 source code encodings, which we'll get to supporting on Jython soon).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;According to the &lt;a href="http://pylonshq.com:8014/"&gt;Pylons on Jython buildbot&lt;/a&gt;, only a few of the Pylons dependency's tests fully pass -- but most of the failing tests are due to unicode issues (again, lack of PEP 263), CPython dict ordering assumed in doctests, and a few other issues that aren't important enough to cover here. Pylons own test failures are only due to unicode issues and lack of support for the Kid and Cheetah templating engines, which Pylons is only testing for the sake of testing alternative templating engines anyway.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The biggest problem with Pylons on Jython so far is running it in development mode with &lt;span style="font-weight: bold;"&gt;paster serve --reload&lt;/span&gt;, which hot reloads your WSGI app whenever a change to one of its files is made. The paster reloader is working but the reloading process is very slow on Jython. Reloading is done by spawning 2 processes; when a file changes, the child process serving your app exits and the parent creates it anew (last time I looked Django and CherryPy's reloaders also work this way). Since CPython startup time, including loading of the entire WSGI app, is pretty quick, this is the safest and probably easiest way to accomplish a reload.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Unfortunately Jython suffers from a lenghty startup time. It takes about 1.5 seconds best case scenario just to get the &lt;span style="font-weight: bold;"&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&lt;/span&gt; prompt in Jython on my 2.33ghz MacBook Pro. It takes almost 10 seconds to get &lt;span style="font-weight: bold;"&gt;paster serve --reload&lt;/span&gt; to fully load a simple Pylons app; that's the parent process startup time plus the child process startup time plus the app load time.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I've been experimenting with using &lt;a href="http://fwierzbicki.blogspot.com/2007/05/playing-with-nailgun.html"&gt;Nailgun&lt;/a&gt; to improve startup time, but it actually isn't helping Pylons' startup time as much as I thought it might. Jython must have a startup time bottleneck or two that we need to find here.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Nailgun also poses other problems, such as when System.exit()'ing resources like sockets and files are left open unless they're explicitly cleaned up. Worse yet, threads are left running -- and Pylons' &lt;span style="font-weight: bold;"&gt;paster serve&lt;/span&gt; by default loads 10 listener threads.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If we can't drastically improve the startup time issue in Jython sooner rather than later, we can probably come up with a reloader for Jython for the time being that doesn't require a full restart. These can be &lt;a href="http://blog.dscpl.com.au/2007/03/reloading-of-python-code-into-web.html"&gt;tricky&lt;/a&gt; and in general are &lt;a href="http://ianbicking.org/docs/Webware_reload.html"&gt;avoided&lt;/a&gt;, though.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Here's a couple screenshots of Pylons on Jython, showing off a handy feature of dynamic languages on the JVM; just having the ability to play around with Java in an interactive interpreter:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;o &lt;a href="http://underboss.org/%7Epjenvey/jython/pylons/Pylons-WebError-on-Jython.png"&gt;Pylons-dev WebError on Jython&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;o &lt;a href="http://underboss.org/%7Epjenvey/jython/pylons/Pylons-paster-shell-on-Jython.png"&gt;Pylons paster shell on Jython&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Pylons is also making progress towards an additional release, 0.9.7, which will utilize the work done by the PyCon sprinters (particularly on WebHelpers), &lt;a href="http://pythonpaste.org/webob/"&gt;WebOb&lt;/a&gt;, WebError (and maybe &lt;a href="http://pythonpaste.org/webtest/"&gt;WebTest&lt;/a&gt;) and will also include optional support for a basic SQLAlchemy configuration for new projects. As well as Alpha Jython support.</content><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://dunderboss.blogspot.com/2008/05/you-must-construct-additional-pylons-on.html' title='You Must Construct Additional Pylons (on other VMs)'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=1772927538588141564&amp;postID=8040054231671637363' title='1 Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://dunderboss.blogspot.com/feeds/8040054231671637363/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://dunderboss.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/8040054231671637363'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1772927538588141564/posts/default/8040054231671637363'/><author><name>Philip Jenvey</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/17437958274873977298</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-1772927538588141564.post-1424303426946460405</id><published>2008-02-08T23:15:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2008-02-09T12:13:51.312-08:00</updated><category scheme='http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#' term='jython'/><category scheme='http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#' term='python'/><category scheme='http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#' term='pylons'/><title type='text'>setuptools on Jython</title><content type='html'>A couple weeks ago setuptools added &lt;a href="http://svn.python.org/view?rev=60062&amp;amp;view=rev"&gt;support for Jython trunk&lt;/a&gt;. This was made possible with a &lt;a href="http://wiki.python.org/jython/SetuptoolsOnJython"&gt;number of additions and fixes to Jython for setuptools&lt;/a&gt;, including distutils and file descriptor support.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A working setuptools is the first big step in getting &lt;a href="http://wiki.python.org/jython/PylonsOnJython"&gt;Pylons working on Jython&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="http://wiki.python.org/jython/DjangoOnJython"&gt;Django on Jython&lt;/a&gt; has had some &lt;a href="http://www.theserverside.com/news/thread.tss?thread_id=47992"&gt;recent success&lt;/a&gt;; luckily for them Django doesn't rely on/use setuptools at all. So &lt;a href="http://blog.leosoto.com/"&gt;Leo Soto&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://zyasoft.com/pythoneering/"&gt;Jim Baker&lt;/a&gt; and the rest of the Django on Jython folks were able to skip directly to kicking around the Django code on Jython.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Now that we have setuptools, the next step is to go through each of Pylons dependencies and ensure their tests pass. Pylons as well as some of its dependencies use the &lt;a href="http://somethingaboutorange.com/mrl/projects/nose/"&gt;nose test runner&lt;/a&gt;. Nose is almost fully working on Jython (after I submit a few upstream patches to nose).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Other dependencies (such as Paste and Beaker) use py.test for their test runners, but there's been some talk of moving some of these over to nose -- which would actually be a good thing right now for Jython. Though technically nose could run through these projects' tests as they already are, they rely on some py.test functionality, such as py.test.raises.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Not to bad mouth py.test -- it has some nice features, like distributed testing -- but I attempted get it working on Jython during the TurboGears 2 sprint a few weeks ago and it wasn't a small task. Part of the problem is the fact that py.test is part of the larger py package. py isn't just a test runner, it also includes other packages that are intertwined with test portion -- all of which need to work before you're able to use just py.test.</content><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://dunderboss.blogspot.com/2008/02/setuptools-on-jython.html' title='setuptools on Jython'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=1772927538588141564&amp;postID=1424303426946460405' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://dunderboss.blogspot.com/feeds/1424303426946460405/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://dunderboss.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/1424303426946460405'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1772927538588141564/posts/default/1424303426946460405'/><author><name>Philip Jenvey</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/17437958274873977298</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email></author></entry></feed>